<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The rates of marchandizes as they are set down in the Booke of Rates for payment of the Kings Majesties customes, and import of wynes within his kingdome of Scotland: the famine booke being signed by his Majestie, and subscryued be the Lords auditors of His Heighnes Exchecker, and sealed with the great seale of his said kingdome. And by special commandement from his Majestie published in print, for the information and direction of all sic as the famine doth concerne.</title>
            <author>Scotland. Commissioners of Customs.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1611</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 212 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 51 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A11644</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 21894</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S110644</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99846150</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99846150</idno>
            <idno type="VID">11098</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A11644)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 11098)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1670:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The rates of marchandizes as they are set down in the Booke of Rates for payment of the Kings Majesties customes, and import of wynes within his kingdome of Scotland: the famine booke being signed by his Majestie, and subscryued be the Lords auditors of His Heighnes Exchecker, and sealed with the great seale of his said kingdome. And by special commandement from his Majestie published in print, for the information and direction of all sic as the famine doth concerne.</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Commissioners of Customs.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[74], 26 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed be Thomas Finlason,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1611.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Decorative panel at head of title page.</note>
                  <note>At foot of title: with the Kings Majesties Licence.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tariff --  Scotland --  Tables --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Tariff --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:11098:1"/>
            <p>THE RATES OF MARCHANDIZES as they are ſet down in the Booke of Rates for payment of the Kings Majeſties Cuſtomes, and Impoſt of Wynes within his Kingdome of SCOTLAND:</p>
            <p>The ſamine Booke being ſigned by his Majestie, and ſubſcryued be the Lords auditours of his Heighnes Exchecker, and ſealed with the great Seale of His ſaid Kingdome.</p>
            <p>And by ſpecial commandement from his Majestie published in Print, for the information and direction of all ſic as the ſamine doth concerne.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>printer's device: crown</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>EDINBURGH, Printed be THOMAS FINLASON. 1611.</p>
            <floatingText type="license" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <p>With the Kings Majesties Licence.</p>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
         </div>
         <div type="letter_patent">
            <pb facs="tcp:11098:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:11098:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <q>.A. VIRTVTE. ORTA. .OCCIDVNT. RARIVS.</q> 
               <hi>James R.</hi>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>crown</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <hi>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>AMES by the</hi> Grace of God, King of <hi>great Britaine, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> defender of the Faith, &amp;c.</signed> 
               <salute>To our Treaſurer, Lords, auditours of our Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>checker, and to all our Cuſtomers and Search<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers at any of our Ports, Havens or Creckes, within our Kingdome of <hi>Scotland</hi> being for the tyme, and to all and ſundrie our others leiges and ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects whom it effeirs to whoſe knowledge theſe preſents shall come, or whom the ſamine doth concerne greeting.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſameikle as in ane general convention of our three Estates of our ſaid Kingdom halden in our burgh of <hi>Dondie</hi> vpon the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:11098:3"/> xiij day of May the yeare of God <hi>1597.</hi> yeares, vpon very good conſiderations, It was thought meet, ſtatute and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deined, that all claith and others waires and merchandize to be brought within our ſaid Kingdome from foraine Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions should in all tyme there-after pay to vs the custome following. That is to ſay, twelue pennies for every pounds worth thereof: And to that effect, we and our ſaids Eſtates gaue full power and commiſsion to a competent nomber of the Lords auditors of our Exchecker and others of our Nobilitie and Councell, to ſet pryces vpon the ſaids waires and mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandizes, conforme to the whilk our Customers to be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poynted to that effect should collect and vp-lift our cuſtome thereof. And as it is well known to al men of judgment and vnderſtanding that this ſpeciall prerogatiue (amongst many others) hath by the laws of Nations bene yeelded and acknow<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ledged to be proper and inherent in the perſons of Princes, that they may according to their ſeverall occaſions raiſe to them-ſelues ſic competent meanes by taking of cuſtome of wares and merchandizes tranſported out of their Kingdoms or broght within the ſamine, as to their wiſdomes and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretions shall ſeeme expedient ſufficientlie to ſupplie and ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtein the great charges and expenſes incident vnto them in the menteinance of their Crownes and dignities (ſo the ſame be done without prejudice of trade and traffick) Even ſo it is moſt certaine that we are a free Prince, of a Soveraigne power, hauing als great liberties and priviledges by the laws of our ſaid Kingdome and priviledge of our Crowne and
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:11098:3"/> Diadame, as any other Prince or Potentate whatſomever. And therfore may alter, raiſe and diminish our cuſtomes as the pryces of wares and merchandizes doeth ryſe or fall. Jn conſideration whereof, and becauſe we are credibille in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed that diuers wares and merchandizes conteined in the <hi>A B C</hi> of our cuſtomes of our ſaid Kingdome, are there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in valued and rated at lower pryces then they should be, to our great loſſe and hinderance; and that divers of the ſaids wares and merchandizes are valued and rated at over heigh and deare a rate, to the great prejudice and hurt of the Merchant; and that divers wares and merchandizes both of thoſe that are brought within our ſaid Kingdome, and of thoſe that are tranſported out of the ſamine are not at all valued nor mentioned in the ſaid <hi>A B C,</hi> whereby the cuſtomes therof hath hitherto bene taken only by the eaths of the merchants awners of the ſaids wares and merchandizes. <hi>FOR REFORMATION</hi> whereof, and to the intent that all ſic wares and merchandizes as at any tyme after the firſt day of November next to come shall be brought into our ſaid Kingdome or tranſported forth thereof, may reaſonablie and indifferentlie be valued and rated both for the true pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to vs of our cuſtome and for the eaſe of the merchants, we haue latelie given power and direction to ane competent nomber of the Lords of our Councell and auditors of our Exchecker, to try and examine what reaſonable and indiffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent values and pryces may and ought to be ſet vpon ilk ſort of the ſaids wares and merchandize; and there-vpon to
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:11098:4"/> make and ſet downe ane Booke of Rates and valuation, to the effect our Cuſtomers may know what to take, and the Merchant know what to pay for the cuſtome thereof. And that it may appeare what care we haue to avoid the leaſt in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>convenient or grievance that may aryſe to our people, we gaue ſpeciall direction to the ſaids Lords of our Councell and Exchecker, that in ſetting downe of the ſaid Booke of Rates and valuation, they should haue a ſpeciall regarde to the ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting of the ſamine orderlie, and to forbeare to value at ane heigh rate ſic commodities imported within our ſaid King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome, as our poore people within the ſamine could not goodly want; or might giue occaſion to the Merchants to raiſe the pryces thereof, ſic as Victuall, Pick, Tar, Hemp, Lint, Iron, Soap, Tackle, Cordage, and others of the lyke nature. VVhilks Lords ſo appoynted by vs haue ſet down this preſent Booke of Rates and valuation accordingly, and reported the ſamin to vs ſubſcryved with their hands, the Originall conteining fourtie leaues written on both the ſides. VVhilk Booke we haue for the better authoritie thereof lykwyſe ſigned with our awn hand, and haue ordeined our great Seale of our ſaid Kingdome to be appended and hung there-vnto, and ordeins this ſamine Booke to remaine amongst our Records and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſters of our ſaid Kingdom. And therfore <hi>WE WIL AND DECLARES,</hi> and for vs and our ſucceſſors, decernes and ordeins that there shall be for ever after the ſaid firſt day of November next to come after the date hereof, taken and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceaved by our Customers to our vſe twelue pennies of every
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:11098:4"/>pounds worth of all wares and merchandizes conteined in the ſaid Booke of Rates, that shall either be tranſported out of our ſaid Kingdome, or imported within the ſamine, as for the cuſtome due to vs for the ſamine wares and merchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dizes (wynes, gould and ſilver onely excepted) The impost of which wynes is particularlie ſet down by it ſelfe in ane ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tickle at the end of this preſent Booke of valuation and rates of merchandizes and goodes imported within our ſaid King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome; and the custome of the ſaid gould and ſilver (incaſe the ſamine shall be tranſported out of our ſaid Kingdome vpon licence) is ſet down by it ſelf in ane artickle at the end of this preſent Booke of Rates and valuation of wares and mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandizes exported out of our ſaid Kingdome. And for this effect, <hi>WE</hi> do by theſe preſents ordein and command all our Customers, Searchers, and others hauing entreſſe in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceit of our cuſtomes at every Port, Haven or Harberie with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in our ſaid Kingdome, that after the ſaid firſt day of No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vember next to come, they and ilk ane of them demand, vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lift, and take of all our leiges or strangers that shall happen to tranſport out of our ſaid Kingdome to foraine Nations or or import within the ſamine from foraine Nations any of the goods, merchandizes or wares conteined in the ſaid Booke of Rates, twelue pennies for every pounds worth thereof, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording as the ſamine is valued and rated in the ſame Booke as for the Cuſtome due to vs, our heires and ſucceſſours for the ſamine: And that they demand, vp-lift and take of im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>post for every tun of wyne that shall happen to be imported
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:11098:5"/> and broght within our ſaid Kingdome after the ſaid firſt day of November next to come, the ſumme of money ſet downe in the ſaid Booke of Rates; and for every pounds worth of coyned gould or ſilver caried out of our ſaid Kingdome vpon licence, the due cuſtome likwyſe ſet down in the ſaid Booke of Rates. And incaſe it shall happen any merchandizes, goods or wares either to be tranſported out of our ſaid Kingdome to foraine Nations, or brought within the ſame from foraine Nations, whilks ar not conteined and ſet down in this preſent Booke of Rates. <hi>OVR WILL AND PLEASVRE IS</hi> that the ſame shall be valued by the Merchant awner there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of or his factours, vpon their eaths of fidelitie, ſolemnedlie giuen in preſence of our Cuſtomers, and that our cuſtome shal be taken thereof accordinglie. And we ordaine all Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants als well our borne ſubjects of our ſaid Kingdome as ſtrangers, to obſerue, fulfil and obey this our ordinaunce con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the payment of our cuſtomes, vnder the paine of in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curring our heigh diſpleaſure, and as they will anſwere to the contrarie vpon their perrell. As likwiſe we ordaine the Lords of our Privie Councel and auditors of our Exchecker of our ſaid Kingdom, to direct letters for anſwering and pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment making to our Cuſtomers of the cuſtome of merchandi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zes, goods and wares, and impoſt of wynes ſet downe in this preſent Booke of Rates and valuation dew to vs, after the ſaid firſt day of November next to come in ſic ample forme, and vnder the like paines as they haue bene accuſtomed to di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect letters for the like cauſe of before. Provyding alwiſe,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:11098:5"/> like as <hi>OVR WILL AND PLEASVRE IS</hi> that if at any time hereafter it shall plainlie appeare to our Theſaurer and Lords of our Councell and auditors of our Exchecker of our ſaid Kingdome being for the time, that the rate, value, kynd, name, lenth or weght of any goods, wares and merchandizes conteined in this preſent Booke be miſtaken or wrong va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lued contrair the treuth and our true meaning in that behalf. In that caſe, we doe by theſe preſents giue full power and commiſsion to our ſaid Theſaurer, Lords of our Councell, and auditours of our Exchecker, or any elleven of them conjunct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lie (our ſaid Theſaurer being alwiſe ane) to reforme the ſame Booke according to our true meaning in every pointe. And we ordein the Clerk of our Regiſter and Rolles of our ſaid Kingdome to deliver to every Cuſtomer or collector of our cuſtomes at every Port, Haven or Harberie within our ſaid Kingdome, a juſt extract of this preſent Booke of Rates and valuation vnder his ſigne and ſubſcription manuell, for their better warrant, to aske, craue, receaue, intromet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with, and collect our ſaids cuſtomes. And theſe our let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters patents, or the juſt extract therof ſubſcrived by our ſaid Clerk of our Register and Rolles, shall be as well vnto you our ſaid Theſaurer, Lords of our Privie Councell, and audi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tours of our Exchecker, as to all other our Cuſtomers, offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciers, and others whom it shall or may appertaine, and to e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very ane of you a ſufficent warrant and diſcharge for doing and performing all and ſundrie the premiſſes according to to our true intent and meaning, any law, ſtatute, order or
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:11098:6"/> vſe heretofore made to the contrair not withſtanding. Giuen vnder our Signe Manuell at our Manor of <hi>Green-witch</hi> the xxix day of Apryle, and of our Raignes the fourtie fiue and eight yeares. <hi>1611.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:11098:6"/>
            <head>THE RATES AND Valuation of Merchandizes and goods imported within the Kingdome of Scotland.</head>
            <div n="A" type="part">
               <head>A</head>
               <list>
                  <item>AIres, <list>
                        <item>of ſmall ſort the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>—<hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                        <item>of great ſort the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                           <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx. l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Allabaſter the load <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiij l.</item>
                  <item>Allum <list>
                        <item>rough the hundreth weght cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xij l.</item>
                        <item>Plume the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viij s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Amber
<list>
                        <item>the pound weight thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx. s.</item>
                        <item>beads the pound thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiij l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Anchoves the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iij l.</item>
                  <item>Anneill of Barbarie for litſters the pound weght therof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviij s.</item>
                  <item>Apples called <list>
                        <item>Pippins or Rannets the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iij l.</item>
                        <item>Flanders apples the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Aquavitie the barrell conteining ten gallons <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                  <item>Arro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wes <list>
                        <item>for tronkes the groſſe conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiij l.</item>
                        <item>called ſhooting arrowes the groſſe <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiij l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Aſhes called <list>
                        <item>Pot aſhes the barrell conteining two hundreth pound weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Wood or ſoap aſhes the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Axes the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vj l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="B" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:7"/>
               <head>B</head>
               <list>
                  <item>BAbies or puppets for children the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iij l.</item>
                  <item>Bagges
<list>
                        <item>with locks the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>with ſteel rings without locks the doz. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.xiii s.iiii d</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Baieberries the hundreth weght conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Ballances called
<list>
                        <item>gold ballances the groce cont. 12 doz. pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiij l</item>
                        <item>ounce ballances the groce cont. 12 doz. pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>pile weghts the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viij s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Balles called
<list>
                        <item>Catchpule balls the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Golf balls the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxij s.</item>
                        <item>waſhing balls the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Bands called Flanders bands the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viij l.</item>
                  <item>Bankers of verdure the dozen peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Barbers aprons the peece conteining not aboue ten els <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiij l.</item>
                  <item>Barilia or ſaphora to make glas, the barrel cont. ij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Barlings or fire poles the hundreth conteing vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Barke the boll thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Baskets called
<list>
                        <item>hand-baskets the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                        <item>round baskets the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Baſons
<list>
                        <item>of Latten the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>of tin the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Beades
<list>
                        <item>of Amber the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of bone the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s</item>
                        <item>of box the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>of Criſtell the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of glaſſe and wood the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                        <item>of Jaſper the hundreth ſtones <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Beanes the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Beer the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:7"/>
                  <item>Beif the punſcheon <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l</item>
                  <item>Beere called
<list>
                        <item>Engliſh beere, the tun <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Dutch beere the laſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Belles
<list>
                        <item>called Hawkes belles, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>called Dog belles the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                        <item>called Moreis belles, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>called Horſe belles, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>called clapper belles the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Bell mettell the hundreth weght conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Belts
<list>
                        <item>called buffill belts, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>called lether belts the groce conteining 12 doz <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>of worſet the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke or velvet gilt the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke or velvet vngilt the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of counterfute gould and ſilver the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>called hingers of buffil the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>caled hingers of lether plane the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>called hingers of lether broudered, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l. l.</item>
                        <item>called hingers of ſatine or velvet plane the doz. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx. l.</item>
                        <item>called hingers of ſatine or velvet broudered with ſilke, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xcvi l.</item>
                        <item>called hingers of ſatine or velvet broude<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red with gould and ſilver the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>called hingers imbroudred with pearle the pece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> c l</item>
                        <item>called ſword belts of lether of all collours, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiij l.</item>
                        <item>called wemens belts imbroudered with jeat, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>called wemens belts embrodered with gold and ſilver, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviij l.</item>
                        <item>called wemens belts embroudered with pearle, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:8"/>
                  <item>Beds
<list>
                        <item>of Oake or Walnut tree French making the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                        <item>of Engliſh making the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Bird lyme the hundreth weght conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviij l.</item>
                  <item>Bitts for brydles the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Blacking or Lamp-black the hundreth weght contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiij l.</item>
                  <item>Blankets called
<list>
                        <item>Paries Mantles cullored the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Paries Mantles vncullored, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l,</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Boords called
<list>
                        <item>Norroway dailles the hundreth cont. 120 <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Spruce dailles the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xc l.</item>
                        <item>Boorden-doore dailles the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Knapald of Norroway the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Knappald of Queens-bridg or double Knap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pald the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>ſingle Knappald or Trail-ſound K. the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Pipe ſtaues the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Barrel ſtaues the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Swaden boordes the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>for boats the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>Table boords of Wainſcot or Walnut tree long, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Table boords of Wanſcot or Walnut tree ſhort, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Wanſcot of Danskene the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ij. c l.</item>
                        <item>Wanſcot of Swaden the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> jc. xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Boats
<list>
                        <item>of ſex oares the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>of foure oares the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiij l. vj s. viij d.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Bodkins the groce conteining twelue dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Bomſpares the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                     <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Bombaſies or borrets
<list>
                        <item>narrow the ſingle peece cont. 15 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>broad the ſingle peece cont. 15 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:8"/>
                  <item>Bonnets called Mantua bonnets and Engliſh bonnets, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Bo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>nets called
<list>
                        <item>for children, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>night bonnets of ſatine and velvet ſteiked, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>night bonnets laid with gould or ſilver lace, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>night bonnets of ſilke knit, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>night bonnets of wooll the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Mariners bonnets the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Borrels for wrights the groce conteing 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Boſſes for brydles, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Botanos or peeces of linning litted blew, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Bottels of earth the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Boultel raines the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l s.</item>
                  <item>Bowes called
<list>
                        <item>hand-bowes the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>pellet or croſ-bowes the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Bowſtaues the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                     <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                  <item>Bowſtrings the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                  <item>Boult-cloth the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                  <item>Box-peeces for making of combes the 1000 peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Boxes called
<list>
                        <item>fire or tunder boxes the groce cont. 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>neſt boxes, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>round buiſtes for Marmalad, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>ſand buiſtes, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Soape boxes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> liii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>touch boxes covered with lether, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                        <item>touch boxes covered with velvet, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>touch boxes of yron or other mettels gilt, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Bracelets
<list>
                        <item>of glaſſe, the groce conteining 12 bundels <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>of corrall, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:9"/>
                  <item>Braſell, <hi>
                        <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>id. Wood. Cuſtome.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Braſſe, the hundreth weght thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Braſen worke, ſic as Landiers, Chandellers, Baſons, cocks of barrels, weghts, and all other made worke the pound weght thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Brick called
<list>
                        <item>brickſtones, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>paviment tyles, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Brimſtone the hundreth weght conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Briſtles
<list>
                        <item>rough or vndreſt the 12 pound weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>dreſt the 12 pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Brotches of Latin or Copper the groce cont. 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Bruſhes or ſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges
<list>
                        <item>of hather courſe, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>of hather fyne, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l,</item>
                        <item>of hair called head bruſhes the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of heath called head bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>of hair called rubing bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>of hather called rubing bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>of hair called combe bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>of hair called weavers bruſhes the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>for ſpounging of cloaths, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>called water ſponges for Chirurgians, the pou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>d <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Buckaſie the haill peece conteining two halfe peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Buckrams
<list>
                        <item>of Germane or fyne buckrame the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of the Eaſt countrie the roul or halfe peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s</item>
                        <item>of French making the dozen peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Carrick buckrame the ſhort peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Buffill hydes the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Bugle
<list>
                        <item>great, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>ſmall or ſeed bougle the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>lace the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l s</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Bullions for purſes the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Burn-wood. <hi>Vid. wood. Cuſtome.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:9"/>
                  <item>Buskeins of lether, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl.l.</item>
                  <item>Buſtiams or woven tweill ſtuff, the ſingle peece not a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boue fiftene elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                  <item>Butter of England or Holand the barrel cont. 12 ſtones <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                  <item>Buttons
<list>
                        <item>of braſſe, copper, ſteele or latin, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                        <item>of criſtel the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>of glaſſe, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>of threed, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        <item>of hair, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of gould and ſilver threed the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of fyne damask warke, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="C" type="part">
               <head>C</head>
               <list>
                  <item>CAbinets or counters
<list>
                        <item>ſmall the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>large the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cables the ſtone weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Cable yarne and ſmall towes, the ſtone <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Caddes
<list>
                        <item>the pound thereof in wooll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv s</item>
                        <item>ſpun in yarne, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxii s. vi d.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chalke, the hundrerh weght thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v s.</item>
                  <item>Camels hair the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Calico cop-boord-cloaths, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Candle-ſheares, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s,</item>
                  <item>Candle-weiks the hundreth weght cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Candles of walx, the pound thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                  <item>Canes or Reeds the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Canarie ſeed, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Cant-ſpars or fire poles, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                     <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Canves. <hi>Vid. linning</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Capers. <hi>Vid. grocerie ware.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:10"/>
                  <item>Capravens, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                     <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Cardes called
<list>
                        <item>wollen cardes new, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>wollen cardes olde, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>ſtock cardes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv p.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Carts the groce conteining twelue dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Carpets called
<list>
                        <item>Brunſweik carpets ſtript or vnſtript, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>China carpets of cotton courſe, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>Gentiſh carpets the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>Turkie or Venice carpets ſhort, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Turkie or Venice carpets long cont. foure elnes and vpwards, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l. l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Carrawa ſeeds the hundreth weght cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Carrels the peece conteniing 15 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Caſſes or buiſtes
<list>
                        <item>with wooden combes garniſhed, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>with ſmall Ivorie combes garniſhed the doz <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>with midle ſort Ivorie co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>bs garniſhed the doz <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>with large Ivorie combs garniſhed the doz <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>for combes ſingle the groce cont. 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>for combes double, the groce cont. 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>for ſpectacles gilt, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>for ſpectacles vngilt, the groce cont. 12 doz <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>called needels caſes, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Caskets
<list>
                        <item>of yron ſmall the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                        <item>of yron middle ſort the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>of yron large the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſteele the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Caviare the hundreth weght conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Ceſterns of Lattin or Tin, the pound weght thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Chaffing diſhes
<list>
                        <item>of braſſe or lattin, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>of yron, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of earth, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:10"/>
                  <item>Chaines
<list>
                        <item>for keyes or purſes fine the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>for dogs, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chaires
<list>
                        <item>of walnut tree, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l s.</item>
                        <item>of leather gilt of the great ſort, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>of leather gilt of ſmall ſort, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of carſies embroudered with ſilk or velvet, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>of velvet, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lets
<list>
                        <item>vnwatered the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>watered, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke, <hi>ſee ſilke.</hi>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dillers
<list>
                        <item>of tin, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>of wyre, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cheeſe the hundreth weght conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Chesboards, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Cheſ-men
<list>
                        <item>of wood, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of bone, the groce conteining 12 ſtand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chimney backs
<list>
                        <item>ſmall, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>great, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Chiſſels for wrights, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Citternes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Claricords, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Claſps, the woſpe <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Cleeks to hing hats on, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Cloaks of felt, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Cloth of wooll
<list>
                        <item>called French cloth the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>called Searge of florence, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>the ſingle peece conteining 15 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> c.xx l.</item>
                        <item>counterfute Searge, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>broad Engliſh cloth, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>ſcarlet cloth, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:11"/>
                        <item>York-ſhyre cloth, the dozen elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Denſhyre cairſais the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Perpetuana, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Friſadoes, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Penniſtone freeſe, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l s</item>
                        <item>cotton freeſe, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxv s.</item>
                        <item>bayes, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>kelt or kendall freeſe, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cloth of linning of all ſortes. <hi>ſee. linning.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cloth of gould and ſilver. <hi>ſee ſilkes</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cochaneill the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Coffers
<list>
                        <item>great of Flanders making covered with gilt lether and barred with yron, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>great of Flanders making painted and bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red with yron barres, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>covered with black leather of the greateſt ſort of Engliſh making, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>covered with black lether of the ſmaller ſort of Engliſh making, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>called balhuves, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of French or Flanders making covered with black leather and barred with yron, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cokes for barrels of wood, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                  <item>Comaſhes out of Turkie, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                  <item>Commyn ſeed the hundreth weght cont. ſex ſcore pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Compaſſes
<list>
                        <item>of yron for wrights, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>of braſſe, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>for ſhips, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Collers for dogs, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Copper wroght in made wark, the pound weght thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:11"/>
                  <item>Copper in plaits vnwroght, round or ſquare, the hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth weght conteining ſex ſcore pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Copper brotches, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Copperas
<list>
                        <item>greene, the hundereth weght thereof cont. ſex ſcore pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>white, the pound thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Corbels of oake, the peece thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Cordage, the ſtane weght thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Coriander ſeed the hundreth weght thereof conteining ſex ſcore pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Cork
<list>
                        <item>the hundreth weght conteining ſex ſcore pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>for cordwyners, the dozen of peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cork takets
<list>
                        <item>of yron, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of ſteele, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Corall white or red, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Corſlets compleit, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Counters of latin the pound weght thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Crosbow
<list>
                        <item>lathes the pound thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>threed, the pound thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                        <item>racks, the peece thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Craip
<list>
                        <item>of ſilke or broad craip, the dozen elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>skum craip, the dozen elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>narrow craip, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>curll craip, the ſingle peece cont. 10 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cruell or Mocado ends the dozen pound weght therof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Curten rings, the pound thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Cuſhens
<list>
                        <item>clothes courſe, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>of tapeſtrie, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of needle wark, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cuttle-bone for gould-ſmiths, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="D" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:12"/>
               <head>D</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Daggers
<list>
                        <item>blades, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>for children, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>black with velvet ſheathes the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>gilt with velvet ſheathes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Damask. <hi>ſee linning cloth.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Dates. <hi>ſee grocerie.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Deskes or letterns
<list>
                        <item>of wood painted, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>for wemen to work on covered with cairſais the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>for wemen to work on covered with velvet the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Diacles
<list>
                        <item>of wood, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of bone, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Dornix
<list>
                        <item>with caddes or wooll, the peece cont. 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>with threed, the peece cont. 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x. l.</item>
                        <item>with ſilke, the peece conteining 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>of french making, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Doubles called
<list>
                        <item>harnes plates or yron doubles, the plate <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>harnes plates, the bundle conteining ten plates <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Dudgeon the hundreth peces conteining ſex ſcore <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l. iiii s.</item>
                  <item>Durances, the peece conteining 15 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
               </list>
               <div n="A" type="part">
                  <head>A</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>A Caſia, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Acorus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Adiantum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Agaricus or agarick, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Agnus caſtus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Alcanet, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <pb facs="tcp:11098:12"/>
                           <item>Aloes cicotrina, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Aloes epatica, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Allum roch the hundreth weght cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Allum plume, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Amber greece black or gray, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                           <item>Ameos ſeed, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Amomi ſemen, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Anacardium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Angelica the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Antimoniu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> crudum the C weght cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>d <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Argentum ſublime, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi s.</item>
                           <item>Ariſtolochia longa &amp; rotunda, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Arſnik or Roſalger, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Aſarum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Aſpalathus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Aſſa-foetida, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="B" type="part">
                  <head>B</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>BAlauſtium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxviii s.</item>
                           <item>Balſamum artificiale, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Balſamum naturale, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <item>Bayberries the C. weght cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Barlie hurld or French Barlie the C. weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Bdellium the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Ben album &amp; rubrum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Beniamin, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           <item>Bezar ſtone of eaſt India, the ounce troy <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                           <item>Bezar ſtone of weſt India, the ounce troy <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           <item>Black lead the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Blatta bizantiae the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Bolus communis or Armoniak the C weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Bolus verus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Borax in paſt the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                           <item>Borax refined, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="C" type="part">
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:13"/>
                  <head>C</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>Callamus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Camphire refined, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l. iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Camphire vnrefined, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Cantarides, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           <item>Carraway ſeeds, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Cardomomes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Carpo balſami, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Carrabe, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Carthamus ſeeds, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Caſſia fiſtula, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Caſſia lignea, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Caſtorium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Ceruſſa, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xix l. iiii s.</item>
                           <item>China rootes. the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                           <item>Ciceres, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Ciperus nutes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Civet, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           <item>Coculus Indiae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Coloquintida, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Corall reed and white, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                           <item>Coriander ſeed, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Cortex-gnaci, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Cortex caperum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Cortex tamariſci, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Cortex mandragorae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Coſtus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Cubebs, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Cummin ſeed, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx p.</item>
                           <item>Cuſcuta, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Ciclamen, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Cytrago, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="D" type="part">
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:13"/>
                  <head>D</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>DAucus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Diagredium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Diptamus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                           <item>Dornicum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="E" type="part">
                  <head>E</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>ELeborus albus and niger, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Epithimum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Aes Uſtum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Euphorbium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="F" type="part">
                  <head>F</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>FEnell ſeed, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           <item>Fenugreek, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                           <item>Flory, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Folium Indiae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="G" type="part">
                  <head>G</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>GAlbanum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Galanga, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii s.</item>
                           <item>Generall, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Gentiana, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Ginny pepper, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Grana pinae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Greene ginger, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Gum animi, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Gum armoniak, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Gum caramiae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxviii.</item>
                           <item>Gum tragagant, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Gum elemni, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                           <pb facs="tcp:11098:14"/>
                           <item>Gum hederae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Gum lack, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Gum opopanax, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Gum ſarcocoll, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv s.</item>
                           <item>Gum Serapinum the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Gum taccamahaccae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="H" type="part">
                  <head>H</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>HErmodactilus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Hypociſtis, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="I" type="part">
                  <head>I</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>INcenſe the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Ireos the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxii l.</item>
                           <item>Iſonglaſſe, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                           <item>Jujubes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="L" type="part">
                  <head>L</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>LAbdanum or lapadanum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Lapis calaminaris, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Lapis hematitis, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Lapis Judaicus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Lapis lazuli, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                           <item>Lapis touciae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Lignum aloes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           <item>Lignum Rhodium the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Lignum vitae, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <item>Litharge of gould, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <item>Litharge of ſilver, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                           <item>Lupines, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="M" type="part">
                  <head>M</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>MAnna, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Marmelad, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <pb facs="tcp:11098:14"/>
                           <item>Maſtickwhite, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           <item>Maſtick reed, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Mechoacan, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Mercurie ſublimat, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Methridat venetiae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <item>Millium ſolis, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Mirabolanes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Mirabolanes condited, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Mirtill berries, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Mummia, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Musk, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           <item>Musk codes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           <item>Myrrha, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="N" type="part">
                  <head>N</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>NIgella, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Nitrum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Nutmegs condited, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Nux cupreſſi, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Nux Indica, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Nux vomica, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="O" type="part">
                  <head>O</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>OLibanum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Opium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Origanum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Oſſa de corde cerui, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <item>Oyle the bay, the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xix l.</item>
                           <item>Oyle of mace, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Oyle de ben, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Oyle de mace, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Oyle of almonds, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <pb facs="tcp:11098:15"/>
                           <item>Oyle of Scorpions, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Oleum petroleum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Oleum terebinthiniae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="P" type="part">
                  <head>P</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>PEarle ſeed, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Pellitorie, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Pepper long, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Perroſen, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Pionie ſeed, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Piſtacias, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Pix Burgundiae, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <item>Polium Montanum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Polipodium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii s.</item>
                           <item>Pippie ſeed, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Precepitat, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Pſyllium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="R" type="part">
                  <head>R</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>REed-lead the hundreth weght <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           <item>Rhabarbarum or Rubarb, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                           <item>Rhaponticum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Roſalger, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Roſet, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="S" type="part">
                  <head>S</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>SAl alkali, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Sal Armoniacum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Sal Gem, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Sal Niter, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Sandaracha, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Sandiver, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <pb facs="tcp:11098:15"/>
                           <item>Sanguis draconis, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Sarſaparilla, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxii s.</item>
                           <item>Saſſafras roots, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Saſſafras wood, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Saunders white, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Saunders yellow, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Saunders reed, <hi>aliâs,</hi> ſtock, the G. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                           <item>Scammonie, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           <item>Scincus Marinus, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Scordium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Sebeſteus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Seeds for gardens of all ſorts, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                           <item>Seler montanus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Semen cucumeris, cucurb, citrul, melo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, the pund <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s</item>
                           <item>Sena, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxvii s.</item>
                           <item>Soldonella, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Sperma caeti fine, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Sperma caeti courſe oyle, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                           <item>Spica celtica, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Spica Romana, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Spicknard, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           <item>Spodium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Spunges, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                           <item>Squilla the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Squinanthum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Staechados, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                           <item>Staues-aker, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxi l. xii s.</item>
                           <item>Stibium, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Storax callida, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                           <item>Storax liquida, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Succus liquiritiae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Sulphur vivum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="T" type="part">
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:16"/>
                  <head>T</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>TAmarindes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                           <item>Terra lemnia, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Terra Sigillata, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Thlaſpij ſemen, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           <item>Tornſal, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                           <item>Treacle common, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>Treacle of Venice, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           <item>Turbith, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           <item>Turbith Thapſiae, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Turmerick, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                           <item>Turpentine of Venice, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                           <item>Turpentine common, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div n="V" type="part">
                  <head>V</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Druggs called
<list>
                           <item>VErdigreece, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           <item>Verniſh the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                           <item>Vermilion, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxviii s.</item>
                           <item>Vitriolum Romanum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                           <item>Umber, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                           <item>White leade the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                           <item>Zeodaria, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Dreſſars
<list>
                           <item>of Walnute tree and Aik French making the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                           <item>of Engliſh making, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="E" type="part">
               <head>E</head>
               <list>
                  <item>EBonie wood the hundreth waight conteining ſex ſcore pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:16"/>
                  <item>Eitches for Cowpers, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. xii s.</item>
                  <item>Elephants teeth, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                  <item>Elſone hefts, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                  <item>Elſone blaides, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Emery ſtones for Cutlers, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="F" type="part">
               <head>F</head>
               <list>
                  <item>FAns for gentle-wemen, the pound waight of Oſtritch feathers <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Fans of counterfute Oſtritch feathers, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Feathers
<list>
                        <item>for beds the C. waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>called Oſtretch feathers the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Feather beds new, the peece filled <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Feather bed tyks the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                  <item>Figgs, <hi>ſee grocerie ware.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Fyles, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Fire ſhooles, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Fire ſchoole plaits, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Fiſhes called
<list>
                        <item>Eeles called
<list>
                              <item>Lamper Elees the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                              <item>Pimper Eeles the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>Schaft-kine or Dole Eeles the barrel <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                              <item>Spruce Eeles, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                              <item>Stub Eeles, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxviii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Gull fiſhe the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Haddocks, the barrel <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Hearings
<list>
                              <item>white the barrel <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l. xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                              <item>reed the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                              <item>reed the Cade conteining v<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:17"/>
                        <item>Killing
<list>
                              <item>the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                                 <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxviii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Ling the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                           <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Newland fiſhe
<list>
                              <item>ſmall the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>midle ſort the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                                 <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>great the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Salmon
<list>
                              <item>the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                              <item>Grilſes, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Seale fiſhe, the fiſhe <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Stock fiſhe
<list>
                              <item>Titling the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                                 <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>Cropling the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>Lubfiſhe, the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Whitings, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Flagons
<list>
                        <item>of earth covered with wicker, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of glaſſe covered with wicker, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of glas with vices covered with lether the doz. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>of glas vncovered, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of tin, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Flannell, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Flaskes
<list>
                        <item>covered with lether, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>covered with velvet, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>of horne, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Flocks the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Frank-incenſe the C. waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                  <item>Furres called
<list>
                        <item>Armins, the timber conteining 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Badger skins, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Beare skins
<list>
                              <item>black or reed, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l. xii s.</item>
                              <item>white, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Beaver
<list>
                              <item>skins, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>bellies or wombes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:17"/>
                        <item>Budg
<list>
                              <item>white tawed the C. cont. vjxx <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiii. l. viii s.</item>
                              <item>black tawed, the dozen skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>blak vntawed the C. cont. vjxx <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                              <item>Powles the fur conteining foure panes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                              <item>Navern the C. legs cont. vjxx. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                              <item>Romney, the C. legs cont. vjxx <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. xii s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Calaber
<list>
                              <item>vntawed, the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                              <item>tawed, the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>ſeaſond, the pane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                              <item>ſtage, the pane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Cattes
<list>
                              <item>skins the C. cont, vj xx. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xix l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                              <item>Powlts, the C. cont. vjxx. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l. xii s.</item>
                              <item>Powlts, the mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                              <item>wombes the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Dockers, the timber conteining 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Fitches
<list>
                              <item>the timber conteining 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Foxes
<list>
                              <item>the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                              <item>the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>wo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>bs, powles or peeces, the pane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Foynes
<list>
                              <item>backs, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>tailes the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>Powts the C. conteining vj xx. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>wombs ſeaſoned the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                              <item>wombs ſtag the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Grayes
<list>
                              <item>vntawed the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>tawed the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Jennets
<list>
                              <item>black, raw the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>black ſeaſoned, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>gray raw, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                              <item>gray ſeaſoned, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:18"/>
                        <item>Lamb skins
<list>
                              <item>white or black vntawed, the hundreth conteining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>white or black tawed with the wool the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                              <item>called Morkins vntawed, the hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>called Morkins tawed with the wool the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Letwis
<list>
                              <item>tawed, the timber cont. 40. skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>vntawed, the timber conteining 40. skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Leopards
<list>
                              <item>skins the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>wombes the pane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Lewzernes skins the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Mertriks
<list>
                              <item>the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                              <item>the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxii l.</item>
                              <item>Powtes the pane or mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>gylls the timber <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                              <item>tailes the hundreth con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xix l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Myniver the mantle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Mynkes
<list>
                              <item>vntawed the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                              <item>tawed the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Moule skins the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        <item>Otter skins the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>Ounce skins, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Sables of all ſorts the timber cont. 40 skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xl l.</item>
                        <item>Weazell skins, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                        <item>Wolfskins
<list>
                              <item>tawed the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>vntawed, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:18"/>
                  <item>Wolverings, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Fuſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans called
<list>
                        <item>Amſterdam, Holland or Dutch fuſtians, the peece con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining two half peces of 15 elns the half pece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Baremillians, Cullen, Milan and Weazel fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtians, the peece cont. two half peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Holmes and Bevernex fuſtians, the peece cont. two half peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l. xvi s.</item>
                        <item>Janes fuſtians, the peece cont. two half peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                        <item>Naples fuſtians Tripe or Velure plane, the half peece cont. 7 elns and an half <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Naples fuſtians Tripe or Velure plane, the peece cont. 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Naples fuſtians wroght, called Sparta vel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vet the peece conteining 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Engliſh fuſtians, the peece cont. 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Ousbrow or Auguſta fuſtians, the peece con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining two halfe peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Weazell fuſtians, the peece conteining two half peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="G" type="part">
               <head>G</head>
               <list>
                  <item>GAdza of all ſorts without gould or ſilver the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                  <item>Gadza ſtript with gould and ſilver, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                  <item>Gally
<list>
                        <item>potts, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                           <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiiii l. viii s.</item>
                        <item>Tiles for foot-paces, the foote <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Galles the hundreth waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                  <item>Garlick the hundreth bunſhes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Garrons
<list>
                        <item>ſingle, the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                           <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>double, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:19"/>
                  <item>Garters
<list>
                        <item>of ſilke French making, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke Engliſh making of broad ſort the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke Engliſh making the middle ſort the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke Engliſh making the narrow ſort the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke embroudered at the ends and with freinyes, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Gauntlets, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Gimlets for Vintners, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                  <item>Girdſtings the hundreth conteining ſex ſcore <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s,</item>
                  <item>Girds of yron for Puncheons or Pypes, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Gitterns for Muſick, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Glaſſes for Windoes of
<list>
                        <item>Burgundie white the keſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Burgundie colored, the kiſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Normandie white, the caſe <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Normandie colored, the caſe <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Reniſh the web conteining LX. bunſhes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Danskene, the kiſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>England, the kiſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>the cradle of glaſſe <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Glaſſes called burning glaſſes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                  <item>Glaſſes cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led looking glaſſes
<list>
                        <item>half-pennie ware, the groce cont. 12 doz. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>pennie ware, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                        <item>of ſteele ſmall, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſteele large, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>of Criſtall ſmall, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of Criſtall middle ſort, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of Criſtall large, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:19"/>
                  <item>Glaſſes cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led houre glaſſes
<list>
                        <item>of Flanders making courſe the groce con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of Flanders making fine, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of Venice making, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Glaſſes called
<list>
                        <item>Balme glaſſes<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Vials or Urinals, the C. conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>water glaſſes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii s.</item>
                        <item>Vantoſes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Glaſſes cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led dinking glaſſes
<list>
                        <item>Venice glaſſes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>for drinking of wyne the dozen of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon ſort <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Cowp glaſſes for drinking of wyne the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Glew, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Globs
<list>
                        <item>the pair ſmall <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>the pair large <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Gloues
<list>
                        <item>of Bridges or French making, the groce con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining 12 dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>of Canarie, Engliſh, Millane or Venice making vnwroght, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s</item>
                        <item>of Canarie, French, Engliſh, Millaine or Venice making, vnwroght with gould or ſilver the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of Spaniſh making plane the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>of Vandon, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke knit, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſhambo lether the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſtags lether, the dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Gold &amp; ſilver threed counterfute called
<list>
                        <item>Bridges gold and ſilver the pound conteining 16 ounces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:20"/>
                  <item>Gould and ſilver threed counterfute called
<list>
                        <item>Cap gould and ſilver, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Copper, gould and ſilver vpon pens and rowls, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Cullane gould and ſilver, the maſt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining 30 ounces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>French copper gould and ſilver, the mark waight cont. 8. ounces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Lyons copper, gold and ſilver, the mark weght double gilt, cont. 8 ounces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Gould and ſilver threed vpright called
<list>
                        <item>Venice, Florence or Millaine gold and ſilver the pound cont. 16 ounces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>French or Pareis gould and ſilver, the mark waight cont. 8 ounces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Gould foile, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Gould papers, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Graines French or Ginie the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Graine
<list>
                        <item>powder the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of Civell in Berries and graine of Portugall or Rotta, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Grindſtones for Cutlers, the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                  <item>Croce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie ware called
<list>
                        <item>Abricoes dry, the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Almonds rough the C. waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Annetſeeds the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Cannell the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Clowes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Fuſſes of Clowes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>Dates the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l.</item>
                        <item>Figgs the topnet cont. 30 pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Figs the peece conteining 60 pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Ginger the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>Hams
<list>
                              <item>of Boyen the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                              <item>Dutch hams, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:20"/>
                        <item>Honny
<list>
                              <item>the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                              <item>the tunn <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Licorus the C. waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Maſes the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Nut-megs, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Oyle caled
<list>
                              <item>Civil province Portugal, Minorca or Majorca oyle, the tunn <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xl. l.</item>
                              <item>ſellet oyle, the gallon <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                              <item>Linſeed the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                              <item>trayne oyle, the tun <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Olives
<list>
                              <item>the jar <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                              <item>the hogiſhead <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Oranges, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Pepper the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Ploume dames
<list>
                              <item>of Deep the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>of Burdeaux, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l.</item>
                              <item>of Brunolia the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Pomgranets, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Raiſins
<list>
                              <item>called great Raiſins the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>great raiſins, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                              <item>of the ſunne, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                              <item>of Corinth, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Ryce, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Saiffron the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxv l.</item>
                        <item>Sidrons, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Suggar called
<list>
                              <item>white and hard, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx. l.</item>
                              <item>Candie broun, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx. l.</item>
                              <item>Candie white, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx. l.</item>
                              <item>Caſnet ſuggar, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l.</item>
                              <item>Candeit, Cannel, Sidron, Clow, Nut-meg and Orange, and pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:21"/>
                        <item>Carraway confeit, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Cannell Romane, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Coriander liskie, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> liii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>Cannell, Clow, Ginger, Oringer and Sidron confeit, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxii s.</item>
                        <item>Corſdecitron candeit, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Amber grece musk confeit, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Dragemuskies, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> liii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>Violet and Roſe confeit, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>Roſmarie confeit, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>White and reed Musk tablets the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Maſpynes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l.</item>
                        <item>Scrotchets, confeits and almonds the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>Dry Orenges, Lemonds and Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>baſſet candeit, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Plumdeſcheny, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Peſhe Geneva, the pound candeit <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Venice dry peſhes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Garbelows, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Wet confe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions
<list>
                        <item>preſerved Barbaries, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>preſerved Chirries, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>conſerved Barbaries, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>preſerved Lettus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>paſt of Jeane, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Pomdecoynes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>preſerved Abricoes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Venice Peares, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>preſerved greene Figgs, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Peare de Plum, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>preſerved Plumes, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:21"/>
                        <item>floure de Orange, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Lemons and Orenges, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Ploum de Chinney, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Damaſſens, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Marmalad, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>preſerved Maces and Nut-megs, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Grograins called
<list>
                        <item>Lylles grograins and Mocadoes, the narrow ſingle peece cont. 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Lylles grograins and Mocadoes, the broad ſingle peece cont. 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>of Engliſh making narrow, the ſingle peece of 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>of Engliſh making broad, the ſingle peece conteining 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Reiſſels grograins the peece of 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Turkie grograins, the peece contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Flanders grograins narrow of all ſorts and colours, the ſingle peece con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Gum Arabick the hundreth waight contuining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Gunnes called
<list>
                        <item>Hagbuts, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Muskets, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Piſtolls, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Gun pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der called
<list>
                        <item>Serpenten the C. waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Cornpowder the C waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="H" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:22"/>
               <head>H</head>
               <list>
                  <item>HAdder for ſpounges the hundreth waight con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Hair called
<list>
                        <item>Cammels hair, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>Elkes hair for Saidlers, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Halks called
<list>
                        <item>Falcons, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Goſhalks, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Jerfalcons, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Laneres, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Lanarets, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Spar halks, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Merlions, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Taſſellis of all ſorts, the halk <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Halk-hoods, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Halberts
<list>
                        <item>gilt, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>vngilt, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hammers
<list>
                        <item>with wooden hands great, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>with wooden hands ſmall, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>called horſ-mens hammers, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hards, the ſtane waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Harnes called
<list>
                        <item>Corſlets compleit, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Curaces, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Morrians or head-peeces graven, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Gould or ſilver, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Morrians plane, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Harp-ſtrings, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:22"/>
                  <item>Hattes
<list>
                        <item>of Bever, wooll or hair, the hat <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>French felts lyned with velvet, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>French felts lyned with tafferie the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Flanders felts lyned with velvet, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>Flanders felts lyned with taffetie, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Engliſh felts lyned with velvet, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Engliſh felts lyned with taffetie, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>felts vnlyned, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>for children, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſtraw, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilk ſteiked, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>thrumb hats, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hatbands
<list>
                        <item>of craip vnthraween, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>of craip thrawen, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                        <item>of ſatine round &amp; wroght with lace, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>embroudered and wroght with ſilk and lace, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>embroudered with gold or ſilver, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>embroudered with Pearle, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hemp called
<list>
                        <item>Spruce or Muſcovia, and all other rough hemp, the hundreth waight contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Cullane, Picardie, Roan, and all other ſorts of dreſt hemp, the C. waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hydes called
<list>
                        <item>Buſfill hydes, the hyde <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Kow hydes of Barbarie or Muſcovia, the hyde <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>India hydes, the hyde <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Oxe or Kow hyds of England, the hyde <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>dry hydes of Ireland, the hyde <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Reed hydes or Muſcovia hydes, tanned, cullored</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:23"/>
                        <item>or vncullored, the hyde <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Hart hydes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hilts for ſwords or daggers, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Hoſe
<list>
                        <item>of wollen, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>of Cruell, called Mantua hoſe, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>of worſet Engliſh making, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke. <hi>ſee ſilke.</hi>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hookes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Hoopes, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                  <item>Hornes called
<list>
                        <item>blawing hornes great, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>blawing hornes, ſmall, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>ſhoone hornes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        <item>Oxe hornes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>for lanterns, the thouſand leaues <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Horſes or Meares, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> jc. xx l.</item>
                  <item>Huſſes skins for Fletchers, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="I" type="part">
               <head>I</head>
               <list>
                  <item>IAveling heades, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Jeaſts
<list>
                        <item>of aik, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of fir, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Ieat, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Iewes trumpes, the groce conteining xii dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Indicoe of Turkie and of the weſt Indies, or ritch Indicoe, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Ink for Printers, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Inkhornes and penners, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:23"/>
                  <item>Inſtruments for Barbers and Chirur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gians
<list>
                        <item>Bullet ſcrues, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Inciſion ſheares, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Turcaſſes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Trepans, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Iron called
<list>
                        <item>Spaniſh, Spruce &amp; Swadens iron the ſtane therof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>the ſhip pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvii l.</item>
                        <item>the tun of iron <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> jc.l. l.</item>
                        <item>Oſmonds, the ſtane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Iron
<list>
                        <item>backs for chimneys ſmall, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>backs for chimneys large, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>bands for kettels, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>girds for pypes or puncheons the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Landiers or creepers, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Potts, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Stoves, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>All other made worke of iron, the C. waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Ivorie, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="K" type="part">
               <head>K</head>
               <list>
                  <item>KEames called
<list>
                        <item>of bone, the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>of box-tree, the groce cont. xii dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>light wood keames, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of horne for Barbers, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>of Ivorie, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Horſe keames, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>caſes with woden keams garniſhed the doz <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>with ſmall Ivorie keames garniſhed, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:24"/>
                        <item>caſes with middle ſort Ivorie keames garniſhed, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>caſes with large Ivorie keames garni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>caſes with keames double, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>caſes with keames ſingle, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Kelles
<list>
                        <item>of linnin for wemen, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>of ſilk, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>of gould or ſilver, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Kettels the C. waight containing vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                  <item>Key knops, the groce conteining xii dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Kids, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Kiſts
<list>
                        <item>of iron ſmall or middle ſort, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>of iron large, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>of Ciprus wood, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>of Spruce or Danskene, the kiſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> liii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>painted, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Knappald, <hi>ſee boards.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Knyues called
<list>
                        <item>Almane, Bohemia, and other courſe knyues, the dicker conteining ten knyues <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii s.</item>
                        <item>Fletchers knyues, the dicker contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning ten knyues <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Carving knyues, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Cullane knyues, the groce conteining xii dozen pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>French knyues, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>Glovers knyues, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Penknyues, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Stock knyues vngilt, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>Stock knyues gilt, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:24"/>
                  <item>Knittings, the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Kyne, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="L" type="part">
               <head>L</head>
               <list>
                  <item>LAdilles of latten or iron, the C. waight contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj xx pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Lambes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Lamblack or blacking, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                  <item>Landiers
<list>
                        <item>of latten, the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>of iron, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lanterns
<list>
                        <item>of common ſort, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi s.</item>
                        <item>of Engliſh making fine, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Latten
<list>
                        <item>ſhaven, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>black, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lead
<list>
                        <item>black, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>reed, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>white, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lether called
<list>
                        <item>Bazell lether, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                        <item>barked lether, the dozen hydes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxii l.</item>
                        <item>Muſcovia lether or reed hydes barked, the hyde <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Perfumed lether, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Spaniſh lether, the dozen skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Spruce or Danskene lether, the dozen skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lyme for Litſters, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Linget ſeed, the peck <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                  <item>Lint
<list>
                        <item>of Spruce, Muſcouia, and all other vnwroght lint, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>dreſt or wroght, the C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:25"/>
                  <item>Linnin in peeces litted
<list>
                        <item>Botanos, litted blew, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Imperlings blew, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv s.</item>
                        <item>Linnes blew or reed, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Linnin Cloth or
<list>
                        <item>Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves called
<list>
                              <item>French canves and linnin broad for board-cloths, being an eln an halfe broad, the C. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> jc. xx. l.</item>
                              <item>French Canves and Line narow, broun or white the C. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                              <item>Dutch and Barras Canves, the C elns conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                              <item>Packing canves and Spruce canves the hundreth elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                              <item>Poldavies, the bolt cont. xxviii elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>Spruce, Elbing or Queens-brow can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves, the bolt conteining xxviii elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>Stript or tufted canves with threed the peece cont. xv elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                              <item>Stript, tufted or quilted canves with ſilk, the peece cont. xv elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii. l. x. s.</item>
                              <item>Stript canves with copper, the peece cont. xv elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                              <item>Vandaloſe or Vitterie canves, the C. elns cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                              <item>Working canves for cuſhens narow the C. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                              <item>Working canves broad, the C. elns cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                                 <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l l.</item>
                              <item>Working canves of the broadeſt ſort the C. elns cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                                 <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Callicoes
<list>
                        <item>courſe, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>fine, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:25"/>
                  <item>Linnin cloth called
<list>
                        <item>Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brick
<list>
                              <item>the half peece cont. ſex elns and a half <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                              <item>the peece conteining xiii elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Lawnes
<list>
                              <item>the half peece cont. ſex elns &amp; a half <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>the peece cont. xiii elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                              <item>called Callico lawnes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>Sletia lawne, the peece betwix foure and eight elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Damask
<list>
                              <item>Board-clothing of Holland making the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>Towelling and ſerveting of Holland making, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                              <item>Towelling and ſerveting of Sletia making, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Dor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nick
<list>
                              <item>Board-clothing of Holla<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>d making the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii. l.</item>
                              <item>Towelling and ſerveting of Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land making, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxvi s. viii d</item>
                              <item>Board-clothing of Sletia making, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi s.</item>
                              <item>Towelling and ſerveting Sletia makin, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Brabant cloth the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Embden cloth the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Gentiſh cloth. the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Flemiſh cloth. the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Freaze cloth. And ſo the peece longer or ſhorter after that rate.</item>
                        <item>Holland cloth. And ſo the peece longer or ſhorter after that rate.</item>
                        <item>Broun holland And ſo the peece longer or ſhorter after that rate.</item>
                        <item>Iſingam cloth. And ſo the peece longer or ſhorter after that rate.</item>
                        <item>Overiſels cloth And ſo the peece longer or ſhorter after that rate.</item>
                        <item>Rowſe cloth. And ſo the peece longer or ſhorter after that rate.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:26"/>
                        <item>Cowsfields cloth or plats, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                        <item>Britiſh cloth, the hundreth elns conteining ſex ſcore <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Drilling and Pack-duck, the hundreth elns conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Elbing or Danskene cloth in double ploy, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Hambrow and Sletia cloth broad, the C. elns white or broun <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Hambrow cloth narow, the C. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l. l.</item>
                        <item>Hinderlands, Middle-good and Head-lack the hundreth elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Iriſh cloth, the C. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Lockram called
<list>
                              <item>Treager, the peece conteining j c. elns. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                              <item>Greſt cloth, the peece contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning j c. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                              <item>Dowlas, the peece conteining j c. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Minſters, the roule conteining fiftene hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth elns at vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> to the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v c. l.</item>
                        <item>Ozenbrigs, the roule conteining fiftene C. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi c, l.</item>
                        <item>Soultwitch, the C. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Polonia, Vlſters, Hanovers, Lubek, narow Sletia, narow weſt-Phalia, narow Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fords, plain ſerviting, and all other na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row cloth of heigh Datchland, not otherwiſe rated, the C. elns. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lit called Orchard lit, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Lockets or chapes for daggers, the groce conteining twelue dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:26"/>
                  <item>Locks called
<list>
                        <item>budget or hanging locks ſmall, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                        <item>hanging locks large, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lures for Halkes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Lutes
<list>
                        <item>of Cullon making with caſes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of Venice making with caſes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lut-ſtrings called
<list>
                        <item>Catlings, the groce conteining 12 dozen knots <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                        <item>Minikins, the groce cont. 12 dozen knots <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Litmus for Litſters, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Lynes called fiſhing lynes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="M" type="part">
               <head>M</head>
               <list>
                  <item>MAces, <hi>ſee grocerie ware.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Madder called
<list>
                        <item>croppe Madder, and all other bale Madder the hundreth waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Fat Madder, the hundreth waight contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Malt, the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Mallies, the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                  <item>Maſts
<list>
                        <item>for ſhips, ſmall the Maſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>for ſhips middle, the Maſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>for ſhips great, the Maſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>for boats, the Maſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Match for gunnes, the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ii s.</item>
                  <item>Meall, the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:27"/>
                  <item>Meall, the laſt conteining twelue barrels <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                  <item>Meden or ſtiffing the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Mellaſſes or Rameales, the tun <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx. l.</item>
                  <item>Milſtones, <hi>ſee ſtones.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Miſſellanes, the peece conteining 30 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                  <item>Michridat, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Mocado ends, or Cruell yarne, the dozen pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                  <item>Morters and Peſtels of braſſe, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Musk, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                  <item>Musk-cods, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                  <item>Muſtard
<list>
                        <item>ſeed, the hundreth waight conteining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of Burdeaux, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Mutches called
<list>
                        <item>night mutches of linning plane, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l s.</item>
                        <item>night mutches embroudered with ſilke the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>night mutches embroudered with ſilke and gould, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>night mutches embroudered with gould and ſilver, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="N" type="part">
               <head>N</head>
               <list>
                  <item>NAiles called
<list>
                        <item>Chaire nailes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Cork-tackets of Iron, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Cork-tackets of ſteele, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Copper-nailes, Roſe-nailes, and Saidlers
<pb facs="tcp:11098:27"/> nailes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Head nailes, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>Harnes nailes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>ſmall nailes, the halfe barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>Sprig nailes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                        <item>Tenter hooks, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Needels
<list>
                        <item>the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>called Pac-needels, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Needle caſes, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Nuts called
<list>
                        <item>ſmall Nuts, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Walnuts, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="O" type="part">
               <head>O</head>
               <list>
                  <item>OCker, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Okehame for calking of Ships, the hundreth waight conteining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Onions
<list>
                        <item>the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>the hundreth bunſhes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Onion ſeed, the hundreth waight conteining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvliii l.</item>
                  <item>Orchall for Painters, the hundreth waight con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Oringes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Orpement, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound for Painters <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Orſedew, the dozen of pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Oxen, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="P" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:28"/>
               <head>P</head>
               <list>
                  <item>PAck-threed
<list>
                        <item>in skaines, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>called bottome threed, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Pans
<list>
                        <item>called dropping and frying pans, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>called warming pans, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Paper called
<list>
                        <item>Broun paper, the bundle <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>Cap-paper, the reame <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Demi-paper, the reame <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Ordinarie printing paper, the reame <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Royall paper the Reame <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Painted paper, the reame <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Preſſing paper, the hundreth leaues <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Paſt of Jeane, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Parchment, the hundreth skins conteining ſex ſcore <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Paſments
<list>
                        <item>of gould and ſilver, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>of velvet, the narow ſort the bolt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l. xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>of middle ſort, the bolt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>of the broadeſt ſort, the bolt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xiii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>of worſet, the groce cont. 12 dozen elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Pearling cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led ſewing pearling
<list>
                        <item>of the narow ſort, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>of the middle ſort, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlv s.</item>
                        <item>of the broad ſort, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Pearles called ſeed pearles, the ounce troy <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                  <item>Peares, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                  <item>Peaſe, the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:28"/>
                  <item>Penners, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Pepper, <hi>ſee grocerie ware,</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Petticots of ſilke, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Pewder, the hundreth waight thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                  <item>Picks
<list>
                        <item>without heads, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>with heads, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l. s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Pillies
<list>
                        <item>of iron, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>of braſſe, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>of wood, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Pile waights, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Pintadoes or Callico cop-boord-cloths, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Piſtollets, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Pitch
<list>
                        <item>of ſmall bind, the laſt conteining 12 barrels <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>of great bind, the laſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Plain irons for wrights, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                  <item>Plaiſter, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Plate
<list>
                        <item>of ſilver white and vngilt, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilver parcell gilt, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. x s.</item>
                        <item>of ſilver gilt, the ounce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Plates
<list>
                        <item>ſingle, white or black, the hundreth plates <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>double, white or black, the hundreth plates <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxii l.</item>
                        <item>ſingle, white or blak, the barrel conteining iij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. plaits <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                        <item>double, white or blak, the barel cont. iij <hi rend="sup">c</hi>. plaits <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xcvi l.</item>
                        <item>called harnes plaits or iron doubles, the plate <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>called white iron platers, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Points
<list>
                        <item>of threed, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of Capiton, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Pomgranets, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:29"/>
                  <item>Pots
<list>
                        <item>of earth or ſtone covered, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>of earth or ſtone vncovered, the hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth caſt, conteining a gallon to e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very caſt whether in one pot or in mo <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>called Gally-pots, the hundreth cont. vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>melting-pots for Gould-ſmiths, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>of Iron French making, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>of Braſe, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Powder
<list>
                        <item>Serpentene, the hundreth waight con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Corn-powder, the hundreth waight conteining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Prenis, the dozen of thouſands <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Punſons and gravers for gold-ſmiths, the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Q" type="part">
               <head>Q</head>
               <list>
                  <item>QVaifes
<list>
                        <item>of gould double, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> l. l.</item>
                        <item>of gould ſingle, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſilke, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>of linnin, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>of jeat, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Quick-ſilver, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                  <item>Quilts
<list>
                        <item>of French making, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>of Callico, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of ſatine or other ſilke, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="R" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:29"/>
               <head>R</head>
               <list>
                  <item>RAcks for Croſ-bows, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Rackets, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Rattels for children, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Razers for Barbers, the dicker conteining ten <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                  <item>Reeds or Canes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Ribbens of ſilk of all ſorts, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                  <item>Ribbens of worſet of al ſorts, the groce cont, 12 doz. elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Ropes tarred or vntarred, the C. waight cont. vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                  <item>Roſet the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                  <item>Rings for Courteins, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Ruggs
<list>
                        <item>called Iriſh ruggs, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>called Poliſh ruggs, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Rungs, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                  <item>Ry, the booll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. vi viii d.</item>
                  <item>Red-earth for painters, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="S" type="part">
               <head>S</head>
               <list>
                  <item>SAck-cloth, the roule or peece, conteining 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                  <item>Saddels
<list>
                        <item>of ſteele, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>covered with black lether,, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                        <item>covered with Cairſays, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>covered with velvet, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Saffora, to make glaſſe, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:30"/>
                  <item>Saiffron, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxv l.</item>
                  <item>Saip
<list>
                        <item>of the law Countries, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>of Caſtile or Venice the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Salmon, the laſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xl. l.</item>
                  <item>Sal-peter, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Salt called
<list>
                        <item>white or Spaniſh ſalt, the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>Bay or French ſalt, the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sawes called
<list>
                        <item>Hand-ſawes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Tenent-ſawes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Whip-ſawes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>Leg-ſawes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sayes
<list>
                        <item>of Flanders making colored, the peece conteining 15 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>called Hairſays, the peece conteining 15 elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sciſers, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x. l.</item>
                  <item>Scupes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                  <item>Scheares
<list>
                        <item>for Walkers, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>for Skinners, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        <item>for Seamſters, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>for Tailers, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>called wooll ſheares, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Schooles
<list>
                        <item>vngarniſhed, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>garniſhed with iron, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Searges
<list>
                        <item>of Engliſh making, the ſingle peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>called Searge daſcot or lyning ſearge, the peece conteining 15 elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Schumak or blacking, the hundreth waight con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj <hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                  <item>Silk called
<list>
                        <item>Bridges ſilk, the pound conteining 16 ounces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>Feret or Floret ſilk, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:30"/>
                        <item>Filoſell or Paries ſilk, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Granado ſilk black, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Granado ſilk in culours, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Naples ſilk black, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Naples ſilk in colours, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Pole, Spaniſh ſatine ſilk and Organſine ſilk the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Throwen ſilk, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>Raw long ſilk, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Raw ſhort ſilk or Capitone, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Raw Morea ſilk, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Sleaue ſilk fine or Naples ſleaue, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Sleaue ſilke courſe, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Silk Nubbs or Huskes of ſilk, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s.</item>
                        <item>Borrats of ſilk, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Silks wroght called
<list>
                        <item>Caffa or Damask
<list>
                              <item>the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>Crimoſin or Purple, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>Counterfute half ſilk half threed the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Calimanco the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Cacalopha, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Chamlets
<list>
                              <item>of ſilk, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                              <item>of ſilk tinſeld with gold or ſilver the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Cloth
<list>
                              <item>of gould and ſilver plane, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                              <item>of gould and ſilver wroght, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                              <item>of Tiſſew, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxx l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Silk-Curles, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:31"/>
                        <item>Grograins
<list>
                              <item>of ſilke narow, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                              <item>of ſilke broad, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l.</item>
                              <item>called Tabie Grograins, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Silk-ſay, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l. xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>Pluſh of all colours, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Sattine
<list>
                              <item>Bridges ſatine, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                              <item>Bridges ſatine tinſeld, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>China or Turkie ſatine, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                              <item>of Bolonia, Lukes, Jeane, and al o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Satine of the lyk making out of grain, figoured or plain the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>in graine or right Crimoſin, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                              <item>tinſeld with gold and ſilver, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Silk-ſtockings or hoſe of Millane, or Paries ſhort, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Silk-ſtockings
<list>
                              <item>of Millane or France long, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                              <item>of England or Naples ſhort the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                              <item>of England or Naples long the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Tabins
<list>
                              <item>of ſilke, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                              <item>tinſelled, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Taffeties
<list>
                              <item>Levant taffeties, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxvi s. viii d.</item>
                              <item>Towres taffetie, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l.</item>
                              <item>Naples taffetie, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                              <item>Jeanes taffetie, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>Spaniſh taffetie, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l.</item>
                              <item>Sarcenet of Bolonia or Florence the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                              <pb facs="tcp:11098:31"/>
                              <item>China ſarcenet, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                              <item>Sarcenet with gould and ſilver, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                              <item>Stript taffetie narow, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                              <item>narow ſtript with gould or ſilver the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>tuf-taffetie narow, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                              <item>tuf-taffetie broad, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                              <item>tuf-taffetie ſtript with ſilver, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Velvets
<list>
                              <item>of all colours out of graine, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>right Crimoſin or purple in grain the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                              <item>figoured of al colours out of grain the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>figoured right Crimoſin or Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Scipers or craip called
<list>
                              <item>of ſilke or broad Sipers, the dozen elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                              <item>Scumme Sipers, the dozen elns <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                              <item>narow Sipers, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                              <item>Curll Sipers, the ſingle peece conteining ten elnes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Skins called
<list>
                        <item>Dog-fiſh skins for fletchers, the skin. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> .v s.</item>
                        <item>Gold-skins, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        <item>Goat-skins of Barbarie in the hair, or out of the hair vntanned, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                        <item>Goat-skins tanned, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>Huſſe-skins for fletchers, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                        <item>Kid-skins in the hair, the hundreth contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:32"/>
                        <item>Kid skins dreſt, the hundreth cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>Seale-skins, the skin <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Portugall skins, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Shamway skins, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>Spaniſh, Civile or Cordowan skins the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Spruce skins tawed, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l</item>
                        <item>Lamb skins, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Cunning skins, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>Sheep skins, called ſhorlings the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Tod skins, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                        <item>Mertrik skins, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Otter skins, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>Selch skins, the dicker conteining ten skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Fowmert skins, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Goat skins, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Hart and Hynd skins, the dicker conteining ten skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Dae and Rae skins, the dicker conteining ten skins <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Engliſh wooll skins, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Slip, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Smalts or blew-ſtiffing, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                  <item>Spangles of copper, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Sparres called
<list>
                        <item>double roofe Sparres, the hundreth con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                        <item>ſingle roofe ſparres, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>wicker ſparres, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Aiken roofe ſparres, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Spectacles without caſes, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:32"/>
                  <item>Spoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges or bruſhes
<list>
                        <item>called water ſpounges for Chirurgians the pound waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>of hadder, the dozen courſe <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>of hadder fine, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of hair called head-bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of heath called head-bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>of hair called rubbing bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                        <item>of hadder called rubbing bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>of hair called keame bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>of hair called wobſters bruſhes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of hair for dichting of cloths, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſhes
<list>
                        <item>of wood, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>of braſſe, the dozen. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>covered with lether gilt, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of tin, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Steele
<list>
                        <item>called long ſteele, wiſp-ſteele, and ſuch like, the C. waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>called gad-ſteele, the half barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j <hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Stones
<list>
                        <item>Sklait-ſtanes, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Sleik-ſtanes, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Cane ſtanes, the tun <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Dog-ſtanes, the laſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lxxii l.</item>
                        <item>Mil-ſtanes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                        <item>Quern-ſtanes ſmall, the laſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Quern-ſtanes large, the laſt <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Syth-ſtanes, the hundreth <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Stirop-irons, the hundreth pair thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Stooles
<list>
                        <item>covered with lether, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of aik vncovered, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Strings called Harp, Lutt or Gittern ſtrings, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi s</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:33"/>
                  <item>Swords
<list>
                        <item>blades of Venice, Spaine, Turkie, or fine blades, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>blades courſe of Flanders making, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>mounted vngilt, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>mounted and gilt with gold or ſilver, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Symon, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                  <item>Sythes, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Smiths ſtudies, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="T" type="part">
               <head>T</head>
               <list>
                  <item>TAbles cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led playing Tables
<list>
                        <item>of Ivorie bone, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>of Braſile, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>of common ſort, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Table books
<list>
                        <item>courſe, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii s.</item>
                        <item>fine, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l. xvi s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Takle, the ſtane waight thereof <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Tallow, the barrell thereof conteining C. waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Tapeſtrie
<list>
                        <item>with hair, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                        <item>with wooll, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi s.</item>
                        <item>with caddes, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. xii s.</item>
                        <item>with ſilke, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>with gold or ſilver, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>of gilt lether, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. xii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tarras, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Tar
<list>
                        <item>the barrell of ſmall bind <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>the barrell of great bind <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tazels, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                  <item>Thimbles, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:33"/>
                  <item>Threed called
<list>
                        <item>Birges threed, the dozen pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> ix l.</item>
                        <item>Crosbow-threed, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Lyons or Paries threed, the ball contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning an hundreth bolts <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx l.</item>
                        <item>Owtnall threed, the dozen pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Peecing threed, the dozen pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>Siſters threed, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tyking of the Eaſt countrie, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x s.</item>
                  <item>Tyles called
<list>
                        <item>pavement tyles, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Chimney tyles, the thouſand <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tin
<list>
                        <item>vnwroght, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>wroght, called Pewder, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tincall or Borax vnrefined, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Tin-foile, the groce conteining 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Tin-glaſſe, the C. waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                  <item>Tinſell of
<list>
                        <item>Copper, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>right gold or ſilver, the elne <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tobacco called
<list>
                        <item>Leafe Tobacco, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                        <item>Cane, Pudding or Ball Tobacco, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tooles called carving tooles, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Tow, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Towes
<list>
                        <item>great, the ſtane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>ſmall, the ſtane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Trayes or croches of wood, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi s.</item>
                  <item>Treacle
<list>
                        <item>called Flanders Treacle, the barrell <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>of Jeane, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>of Venice, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:34"/>
                  <item>Trenchers of wood
<list>
                        <item>white of common ſort, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. iiii s.</item>
                        <item>reed or painted, the groce <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>white of the fineſt ſort, the groc <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="V" type="part">
               <head>V</head>
               <list>
                  <item>VElvet, <hi>ſee ſilks.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Veales, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                  <item>Velures,, <hi>ſee Naples fuſtians.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Verditor for Painters, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Vergus, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii s. iiii d.</item>
                  <item>Vernice, the gallon <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                  <item>Vice haſpes, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                  <item>Vice tongs, or hand vices, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. xii s.</item>
                  <item>Vineger, the tun <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Viols, the peece <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Virginals, the pair <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                  <item>Vizards, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="W" type="part">
               <head>W</head>
               <list>
                  <item>WAdmoll, the eln <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Waights of braſſe or pyle waights, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Wainſcot, <hi>ſee boards.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Warming pans, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Walx called
<list>
                        <item>ſoft walx, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>called hard walx, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:34"/>
                  <item>Walkers earth, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Whale fin, the ſinne— xii s.—the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Whale-ſhot, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Weld for litſters, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Wheate, the boll <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Whet-ſtanes, the hundreth ſtanes <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> v l.</item>
                  <item>Whip-cord, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                  <item>Whiſſels for Taberners, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                  <item>Whiſſels for children, the groce cont. 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l. xii s.</item>
                  <item>Wynes of all ſorts, <hi>ſee after the Rates Inwards.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Woad called
<list>
                        <item>Iland or greene woad, the tun con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining twentie hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. lxxx. l.</item>
                        <item>Tholouſe woad, the hundreth waight con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Woad-nets for Litſters, the hundreth waight contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Wood called Fuſtick wood for Litſters, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Worſets called ſewing worſets, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Wood called
<list>
                        <item>Box wood for keames, the thouſand peeces <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Braſeil or Fernando buck-wood, the hun<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Ebonie wood, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>Fuſtick, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Lignum vitae, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Burnwood, the fathome <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Wooll called
<list>
                        <item>Beaver-wooll, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Cotton wooll, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>Eſtridg wooll the hundreth waight contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:35"/>
                        <item>French wooll, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Lambes wooll, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Polonia wooll, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Spaniſh wooll for clothing or felts, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Womils for wrights, the dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                  <item>Worm-ſeed, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxiiii s.</item>
                  <item>Wreſts for Virginals, the groce cont. 12 dozen <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> vii l. iiii s.</item>
                  <item>Wyre called
<list>
                        <item>Iryon wyre, the hundreth waight contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Latten wyre, the hundreth waight con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Steele wyre, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xviii s.</item>
                        <item>Virginall wyre, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Y" type="part">
               <head>Y</head>
               <list>
                  <item>YArne called
<list>
                        <item>Cable yarne, the ſtane <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Cotton yarne, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Raw linnin yarne Dutch or French, the pound <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Spruce or Muſcovia yarne, the hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Wollen or Bay yarne, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Iriſh yarne, the hundreth waight <hi>Cuſtome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:35"/>
               <head>JMPOST TO BE PAYED FOR VVYNES broght in Scotland by Scottes-men or strangers.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>Wynes called
<list>
                        <item>GAſcone and French Wynes, and all other wynes of the French Kings dominions, in Impoſt for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very tunne thereof xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>Reniſh wyne, the Awme in Impoſt vi. l.</item>
                        <item>MUſcadels, Malueaſies, and all other Wynes of the grouth of the Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant ſeas in Impoſt for every tunne thereof xxxvi l.</item>
                        <item>SAcks, Canaries, Malagaes, Maderaes, Romneys, Hulloks, Baſtards, Teynts and Allacants, for every tunne or two Butts or Pypes thereof in Impoſt xxxvi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="illustration">
            <pb facs="tcp:11098:36"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>Royal coat of arms of James I</figDesc>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="rates">
            <pb facs="tcp:11098:36"/>
            <head>THE RATES AND VALV<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ation of Merchandizes and wares tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſported out of the Kingdome of SCOTLAND.</head>
            <div n="A" type="part">
               <head>A</head>
               <list>
                  <item>AIres
<list>
                        <item>of the ſmall ſort, the hundreth contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning ſex ſcore <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>of the great ſort, the hundreth con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining ſex ſcore <hi>Custome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Aſhes called
<list>
                        <item>Pot aſhes, the barrell conteining two hundreth pound waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>wood or ſoape aſhes, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Aqua-vitae, the barrell conteining ten gallons <hi>Custome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                  <item>Aites, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="B" type="part">
               <head>B</head>
               <list>
                  <item>BArrell ſtaues, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Beere, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:37"/>
                  <item>Beefe
<list>
                        <item>the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>the carcage freſh <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Beanes, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Beere, the tun <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Bel-mettell, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                  <item>Billets, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Bird-lyme, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Braſſe, the barrell conteining two hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                  <item>Bridles, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Bridle-bits, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Braſeil, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                  <item>Butter
<list>
                        <item>good, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>corrupt, the barrel <hi>Custome.</hi> xiii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="C" type="part">
               <head>C</head>
               <list>
                  <item>CAbles, the ſtane waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Cable yarne, the ſtane waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Cards called
<list>
                        <item>New wollen Cards, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>auld wollen Cards, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Stock Cards, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Carts, the groce conteining twelue dozen pair <hi>Custome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Cheeſe, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                  <item>Coales called
<list>
                        <item>Smiddie coales, the chalder <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii s.</item>
                        <item>great coales, the chalder, <hi>Custome.</hi> x s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Cordage tarred or vntarred, the ſtane waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:37"/>
                  <item>Corbels of aik, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Copper the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Cloth called
<list>
                        <item>Wollen cloth and pladding of Scottiſh making, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>broad Engliſh cloth, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>Scarlet-cloth, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> xiii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>York-ſhyre cloth, the dozen elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Den-ſhyre Cairſays, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Perpetuana, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xxiiii l</item>
                        <item>Friſadoes, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> v l.</item>
                        <item>Penniſtone freeſe, the elne <hi>Custome.</hi> l s.</item>
                        <item>Cotton freeſe, the elne <hi>Custome.</hi> xxv s.</item>
                        <item>Bays, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Kelt or Kendall freeſe, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="D" type="part">
               <head>D</head>
               <list>
                  <item>DAils called
<list>
                        <item>Norroway dails, the C. conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                           <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Spruce dails, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xc l.</item>
                        <item>Burgendorp dails, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="F" type="part">
               <head>F</head>
               <list>
                  <item>FLocks, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Fuſtians Engliſh making, the peece contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning 15 elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                  <item>Feathers for beds, the ſtane <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="G" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:38"/>
               <head>G</head>
               <list>
                  <item>GLew, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Gloues plain, the groce conteining 12 dozen pair <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Grograine Scottiſh making, the ſteik thereof con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining 15 elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Goates caried in England, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="H" type="part">
               <head>H</head>
               <list>
                  <item>HAlks called
<list>
                        <item>Falcons, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Goſhalkes, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Jerfalcons, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                        <item>Laners, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Lanerets, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Spar-halks, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                        <item>Merlions, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Taſſels of all ſorts, the halk <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hemp ſeed, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Hemp of all ſorts dreſt, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Halbers, the dozen vngilt <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                  <item>Herring
<list>
                        <item>the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l. xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>reed herring, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hyds
<list>
                        <item>Ilk dicker of ſalt Oxen or Kyne hydes of Scotland conteining ten hyds <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Ilk dicker of ſalt Oxen or Kyne hydes of England, conteining ten hyds <hi>Custome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:38"/>
                  <item>Hydes
<list>
                        <item>Ilk daiker of dry hydes conteining ten hydes <hi>Custome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Hoſe
<list>
                        <item>the hundreth pair of hoſe, bonnets and ſocks made of wooll, and wolven in <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Leith-wynd, or other places <hi>Custome.</hi> xl. l.</item>
                        <item>the hundreth pair of worſet hoſe <hi>Custome.</hi> iij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Honney, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Hornes
<list>
                        <item>Buck hornes, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>Hart hornes, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Oxen hornes, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Rams or ſheeps horns, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Horſes or Meares, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Horſ-tailes, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. tailes <hi>Custome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Hookes, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="I" type="part">
               <head>I</head>
               <list>
                  <item>IEaſts
<list>
                        <item>of aik, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>of fir, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Jedburgh ſtaues, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Iron
<list>
                        <item>the ſtane waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>the ſhip pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xvii l.</item>
                        <item>the tun <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l. l.</item>
                        <item>the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> vii l. x s.</item>
                        <item>wroght, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>wroght and auld, the tun <hi>Custome.</hi> lxxv l.</item>
                        <item>Pots, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>ordinance, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="K" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:39"/>
               <head>K</head>
               <list>
                  <item>KEttels, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                  <item>Killing
<list>
                        <item>the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                           <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Knappald
<list>
                        <item>Noroway Knappald, the hundreth con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>Queenſ-brig Knappald the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>ſingle Knappald or Trailſound Knappald the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> v l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Kyne caried in England or Ireland, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="L" type="part">
               <head>L</head>
               <list>
                  <item>LAmbs, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Leade
<list>
                        <item>vncaſt, the fodder conteining two thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand waight <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. lx l.</item>
                        <item>caſt, the fodder conteining two thouſand waight <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. lxxx l.</item>
                        <item>Oore, the barrell conteining fiue hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Leather called
<list>
                        <item>wyld lether, the dicker conteining ten hyds <hi>Custome.</hi> xvil. xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>white lether, the hundreth con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi> 
                           <hi>Custome.</hi> xiii. l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>lether points, the groce contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning 12 dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Linnin called
<list>
                        <item>Scottiſh linnin braid for board-claiths, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Scottiſh linnin narow for ſerveits, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:11098:39"/>
                        <item>Scottiſh dornik broad for board-claiths the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx s</item>
                        <item>Scottiſh dornik narow for ſerveits, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> x s.</item>
                        <item>Danskene linnin, the hundreth elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Lint-ſeed, the peck <hi>Custome.</hi> xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                  <item>Lint
<list>
                        <item>vnwroght, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>dreſt or wroght, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Ling
<list>
                        <item>the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="M" type="part">
               <head>M</head>
               <list>
                  <item>MAder called
<list>
                        <item>Crop Mader, and all other bale Mader the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Fat Madder, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Malt, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Meall, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Maſts
<list>
                        <item>for ſhips ſmall, the Maſt <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>for ſhips of the middle ſort, the Maſt <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>for ſhips great, the Maſt <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>for boats, the Maſt <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="N" type="part">
               <head>N</head>
               <list>
                  <item>NAilles called
<list>
                        <item>Dore nailes, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Garron nailles, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                        <item>Plenſher nailes, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>Tackets-the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Window nailes, the thouſand <hi>Custome.</hi> xxiii s. iiii d.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Nutes called ſmall nutes, the barrel cont. three firlots <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="O" type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:11098:40"/>
               <head>O</head>
               <list>
                  <item>OXen caried in England or Ireland, ilk Oxe <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Oyle, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> xiii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="P" type="part">
               <head>P</head>
               <list>
                  <item>PAns of braſſe, the pound waight <hi>Custome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Pans of Iron, called dropping or frying pans the pound waight <hi>Custome.</hi> i s. iiii d.</item>
                  <item>Paſments
<list>
                        <item>of ſilk, the pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>of velvet narow, the bolt <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l. xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                        <item>of velvet middle ſort, the bolt <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                        <item>of velvet, the braideſt ſort the bolt <hi>Custome.</hi> xiii. l. vi. s. viii. d</item>
                        <item>of worſet or threed, the groce con<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>teining twelue dozen elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xxxvi s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Peaſe, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Penners and inkhornes, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Pewder, the hundreth waight conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xlviii l.</item>
                  <item>Piſtolets, the pair <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Pitch
<list>
                        <item>of ſmall bind, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of great bind, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> v l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Poynts
<list>
                        <item>of lether, the groce cont. 12 dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>of ſilk, the groce <hi>Custome.</hi> xii l.</item>
                        <item>of, threed, the groce <hi>Custome.</hi> x s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Potts
<list>
                        <item>of braſſe, the pound waight <hi>Custome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                        <item>of iron, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:40"/>
                  <item>Powder, the hundreth waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Pype-ſtaues, the hundreth conteining vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Purſes of lether, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> xviii s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="R" type="part">
               <head>R</head>
               <list>
                  <item>RIbbens of ſilke of all ſorts, the pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xxiiii l.</item>
                  <item>Ribbens of worſet of all ſorts, the groce con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teining 12 dozen elns <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Roſet, the hundreth waight cont. vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xvi l.</item>
                  <item>Ry and Ry meall, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="S" type="part">
               <head>S</head>
               <list>
                  <item>SAck-cloth, the role or peece conteining 15 elns <hi>Custome.</hi> v l.</item>
                  <item>Saddels of Scottes making covered, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Saddle-ſtocks vncovered, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Soape, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Salmon, the laſt <hi>Custome.</hi> ij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xl l.</item>
                  <item>Salt called
<list>
                        <item>ſmall ſalt, the barrel cont. twa bolles <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>ſmall ſalt, the chalder <hi>Custome.</hi> viii l.</item>
                        <item>great ſalt, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Salt-peter, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                  <item>Says of Scottes making, the peece conteining 15 elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                  <item>Says of Flanders making colored and vncolored, the peece coteining 15 elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xxxvi l.</item>
                  <item>Searges of Scottes making, the peece cont. 15 elns <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                  <item>Sheep caried in England or Ireland, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Silk of all ſorts, the pound waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:41"/>
                  <item>Skins called
<list>
                        <item>Calf skins, the dacker conteining ten skins <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>clipped skins, the hundreth conteing vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Cunning skins, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> iii. l vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>Fumart skins, called fitchoes, every ten thereof <hi>Custome.</hi> iii. l. vi. s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>Futſels and ſcaldings, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Goat skins, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Lamb skins, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Lentren-ware, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Marekin skins made in Scotland, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx l.</item>
                        <item>Mertrik skins, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s viii d.</item>
                        <item>Otter skins, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> xviii l.</item>
                        <item>Kid skins, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Schorlings, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                        <item>Selch skins, the daicker <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>Tod skins, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                        <item>Veil skins barked, the daicker <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Wooll skins, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> lx l.</item>
                        <item>Wolf skins, the daicker <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sparres called
<list>
                        <item>double rufe ſparres, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> lxxx l.</item>
                        <item>ſingle rufe ſpaarres, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>aik rufe ſparres, the pecee <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>wicker ſparres, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Stuling, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Stirop irons, the dozen pair <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                  <item>Stirop lethers, the dozen pair <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                  <item>Sword-blaids, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Swords monted, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Sword belts of lether Scots making, the dozen <hi>Custome.</hi> iiii l.</item>
                  <item>Swyne, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> v l.</item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:41"/>
                  <item>Suggar called
<list>
                        <item>white and hard, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx l.</item>
                        <item>Candie broun, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx l.</item>
                        <item>Candie white, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx l.</item>
                        <item>Caſnet ſuggar, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sythes, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Seathes
<list>
                        <item>the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> xiii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                        <item>the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> v l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="T" type="part">
               <head>T</head>
               <list>
                  <item>TAkle, the ſtane waight thereof <hi>Custome.</hi> xl. s.</item>
                  <item>Tallow, called Narves tallow, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> x l.</item>
                  <item>Tallow called Scottiſh tallow, tranſported vpon licence, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                  <item>Tar
<list>
                        <item>of ſmall bind, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                        <item>of great bind, the barrell <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>Tyking for beds, the eln <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                  <item>Towes
<list>
                        <item>great, the ſtane waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
                        <item>ſmall, the ſtane waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Ʋ" type="part">
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>
               </head>
               <list>
                  <item>VEales, the peece <hi>Custome.</hi> v l.</item>
                  <item>Vinager of wyne, the tunne <hi>Custome.</hi> xxv l.</item>
                  <item>Vinager of beere <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="W" type="part">
               <head>W</head>
               <list>
                  <item>WAdmoll, the elne <hi>Custome.</hi> viii s.</item>
                  <item>Wainſcot
<list>
                        <item>of Danskene, the hundreth contei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning vj<hi rend="sup">xx</hi>. <hi>Custome.</hi> ij<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. l.</item>
                        <item>of Swaden, the hundreth <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xxx l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:11098:42"/>
                  <item>Walx, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xxx l.</item>
                  <item>Wheat, the boll <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l. vi s. viii d.</item>
                  <item>Whaleſhot, the barrell conteining 40 pound waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                  <item>Worſet yarne, called ſewing worſet, the pound <hi>Custome.</hi> iii l.</item>
                  <item>Wooll caried out of the Countrie vpon licence, the ſtane waight thereof <hi>Custome.</hi> vi l. xiii s. iiii d.</item>
                  <item>☞Wynes of all ſorts in regarde that the ſamine payes a deare impoſt at the incomming, every tun ſal pay of cuſtome at the tranſporting thereof out of the Countrie <hi>Custome.</hi> xl s.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div n="Y" type="part">
               <head>Y</head>
               <list>
                  <item>YArne called
<list>
                        <item>Cable yarne, the ſtane waight thereof <hi>Custome.</hi> xx s.</item>
                        <item>Cotton yarne, the pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Raw linnin yarne Dutch or French, the pound <hi>Custome.</hi> xii s.</item>
                        <item>Spruce or Muſcovia yarne, the hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xx l.</item>
                        <item>Wollen or Bay yarne, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xl l.</item>
                        <item>Iriſh yarne, the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> xv l.</item>
                        <item>Scottes yarne tranſported vpon licence the hundreth waight <hi>Custome.</hi> j<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. xx. l.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>THE CVSTOME TO BE VPLIFTED by his Majeſties Cuſtomers for gold and ſilver tranſported out of SCOTLAND.</head>
               <p>ALL gold and ſilver tranſported out of Scotland vpon licence, shall pay to his Mjaestie in Custome of every pounds worth thereof — iij s. iiij d.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="acts_and_ordinances">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:11098:42"/>
            <head>CERTAINE ACTS OF PARLIAMENT, AND ORDI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances of Secreet Councell, made anent the payment of the Kings Majesties Cuſtomes and Impoſt of Wynes.</head>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>129</hi> Act of his Maieſties twelfth Parliament the <hi>5.</hi> of Iune. <hi>1592.</hi> Anent the Custome of English gudes, and ſearching of gudes cuſtomable.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>TEM, OVR SOVERAINE LORD And Eſtates of this preſent Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, ratifies, approues and confirmes the act of ſecreit Councel, made vpon the penult day of Februar, ane thouſand, fiue hundreth, foureſcore nine yeares. Anent the bringing of all packs of Engliſh claith haill, vn-broken-vp to the Cuſtome-houſe, and ſelling thereof, in maner conteined there-intill, in all poynts, articles and clauſes, <hi>reſpectiuè</hi> ſpecified in the ſame, with this addition: That na maner of perſons tak vpon hand, to houſe, hyde or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceale any maner of Engliſh gudes, either comming by ſea or land, in any burgh or ſuburbe of this Realme, vnder the paine of confiſcation of all the gudes ſwa hid and concealed, in de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fraud of the due Cuſtome, where ever the ſame can be appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hended.
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:11098:43"/> And incaſe the ſamine be not apprehended, the awners to make the availl thereof forth-comming to his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſtie as eſcheat, after tryell tane there-intill as effeirs. And alſo for the better execution, to ordaine ilk Cuſtomer, to ſearch within the boundes of his office, all maner of houſes and buithes, alſwell to burgh as to land; and to eſcheat, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fiske and intromet-with all maner of vncuſtomed Engliſh gudes, and all Engliſh claiths vnſealed; and if need beis, to make open durres, and other lock-faſt lumes, and to vſe his Majeſties keyes to that effect. And incaſe any perſons reſiſt be force, to make open and patent durres to the ſaid Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, for the effect foreſaid: The perſons reſiſters to be vnder the lyke danger, as the committers of the deforcements, and to be puniſhed in their perſons and gudes, conforme to the act made there-anent. Ordaining alſo, the Proveſt, Baillies and Magiſtrats of ilk burgh, if need beis, to concur and aſſiſt with the ſaids Cuſtomers, in execution hereof, ſwa oft as they fall be requyred there-to.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>89</hi> Act of his Maieſties elleuinth Parliament the xxix of Iulie <hi>1587.</hi> Falſe Cuſtomers and ſearchers ſould be punished.</head>
               <p>ITEM, It is ſtatute and ordained, that all Cuſtomers and Searchers committing fraud in their office, be over-ſight of the tranſporting of forbidden gudes forth of the Cuntrie, for gratitude given to them, ſhall be called therefore at Juſtice Aires, and particular dyets, and puniſhed in their perſons at OVR SOVERAIGNE LORDS will, and all their moveable gudes to be eſcheated to his Heighnes vſe, in-caſe of their conviction.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:11098:43"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>251</hi> Act of his Maieſties <hi>15</hi> Parliament xix of December <hi>1597.</hi> All Marchandize brought within this Realme ſould pay Cuſtome.</head>
               <p>OVR SOVERAIGNE LORD, And Eſtates of this preſent Parliament, ratifies, approues and confirmes the act made at <hi>Dondie,</hi> the thirtenth day of Maij, the yeare of God, ane thouſand, fiue hundreth, ninetie ſeaven yeares, anent OVR SOVERAIGNE LORDS Cuſtomes, of the whilk the tenour followes. FOR-SA-MEIKLE As it is vnderſtand to the Kings Majeſtie, his Nobilitie, Councell and Eſtates, preſentlie conveined, that the ſubjects of all Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raine Nations, whilks brings and tranſports any kynde of claith, or others waires or marchandize, from any Foraine Countrie, to their awne natiue Countrie, hes bene in vſe, and yet ſtill continues in the payment of certaine cuſtome, or other exaction therefore, cheeflie at the tyme of their arrivall, and in-comming within the famine: And almaiſt few or nane of the ſubjects of any Realme exeemed there-fra (the ſubjects of this Countrie onely excepted) wha be reaſon of ane alleaged by-paſt immunitie, claimes the priviledge of exemption: Albeit it can not be denyed bot his Majeſtie is a free Prince, of a Soveraigne power, hauing als great liberties and prerogatiues be the lawes of this Realme, and priviledge of his Crown and Diadame, ay any other King, Prince or Potentat whatſomever: And therefore aught to haue the like cuſtome and exaction, for intertaining of his Princelie Eſtate of al claith and others wares and marchandize to be brought within this Realme, by his Heighnes ſubjects, at all times hereafter. For the whilk purpoſe his Majeſtie with advice of his ſaid Nobilitie, Councell and Eſtates, hes thought meet, concluded and ordeined, that all claith and others Marchandizes what-ſome-ever to be
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:11098:44"/> broght within this Realme from all foraine Nations, ſall pay the cuſtome following, at the tyme of their arrivall and entrie therein, in all tyme comming: That is to ſay, Twelue pennies of every pounds worth of all ſorts of the ſaids wares or mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandize. And to this effect, his Heighnes, and his ſaids No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bilitie, Councell and Eſtates, giues full power and commiſſion to the Lords, Auditours of his Exchecker, and others of his Nobilitie and Councell, to the number alwayes of elleven per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, at the leaſt, to ſet down the <hi>A. B. C.</hi> of the cuſtome of all claith, and others wares and marchandize whilks ſal be broght and enter within this Realme yearlie hereafter: With power lykwaies to them to ſet pryce vpon the ſaids wares: conforme to the whilk the Cuſtomers to be appointed by his Majeſtie to that effect, ſall vp-lift cuſtome thereof: And to make all other ordinances neceſſar for the eaſe of the Marchants, and ſuretie his Heighnes cuſtome, in the execution of the premiſſes. And alſo of ſic others gudes to be tranſported forth of this Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alme, as are not as yet expreſſed in the <hi>A.B.C.</hi> alreadie made. Provyding this act be not extended to Earles, Lords, Barrons and Free-halders; but it ſall be leſome to them, to ſend their gudes beyond ſea, for their awne particular vſe. AND ALS it ſall be leſome to them to bring within this Realme, Wynes, Claiths, and other furniſhings, for their awne particular vſe; and na waies to make marchandize thereof, conforme to the lawes and liberties granted to them of before. The whilk act aboue written, OVR SOVERAIGNE LORD, and Eſtates foreſaids, decernes and declares, to ſtand as ane law in all tyme comming.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:11098:44"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>255</hi> Act of his M. <hi>15</hi> Parliament the xix of December <hi>1597.</hi> All Cocquets ſould be ſpeciall, and conteine the particular kyndes of Marchandize.</head>
               <p>ITEM, It is ſtatute and ordeined, for eſchewing of the dam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nage and skaith whilk daily aryſes throw generall and infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mall Cocquets, given and granted within this Realme. That in all tymes comming all Clerks of the Cocquet, ſall patticu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larlie expreeme and ſpecifie in the Cocquets given by them, the particular quantities of the gudes and marchandizes, the ſpeciall kindes and ſortes thereof, the names of the Marchants and awners of the ſamine, how meikle of the ſame gudes per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teines to ilk Marchant: And that the Conſervatour in the <hi>Law-Cuntries</hi> admit nor allow any Cocquet, except it be written and formed in maner foreſaid, bot ſall confiſcat all the ſaids gudes, not expremed particularlie, as ſaid is: And make compt and reckoning thereof yearlie to the Theſaurer, as he will an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwere vpon his office.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>257</hi> Act of his M. <hi>15</hi> Parliament the xix of December <hi>1597.</hi> The eath of the Marchants, Skippers and Factours paſſand to and fra the Law-cuntries, and forth of this Realme.</head>
               <p>ITEM, The Conſervatour ſall not receaue nor admit any Cocquet, albeit the ſame be lawfullie given, except the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants, Skippers, Factours, and every ane of them before the loſſing of any of their gudes, make faith, and ſweare ſolemnedly be GOD himſelfe his Creator, that he hes na forbidden gudes or geare, nor na other vnlawfull merchandizes, by and attour that whilk is conteined in the Cocquet, nor knawes of nane to be in the ſamine ſhip perteining to others: And that ſa far as
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:11098:45"/> he vnderſtands, the haill gudes and geare perteins properlie to free men, and na part thereof to vnfree-men. As alſo at their back returning from the <hi>Law-Cuntries</hi> towards <hi>Scotland,</hi> they ſall lykwyſe giue their ſolemne eathes, before the laidning of the ſhip, or inputting of any gudes, that the gudes properlie pertaines to them-ſelues, and not to ſtrangers. And if they loſſe any gudes and geare comming from <hi>Scotland,</hi> before the giving of the ſaid eath, or puts any gudes in ſhip-burde, to be tranſported towards <hi>Scotland,</hi> all the ſame gudes to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fiſcate. And if the ſaid eath be refuſed be them all, and they na wayes will make the ſame. It ſall be leſome to the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervatour to arreiſt the ſaid Shippe, and all the gudes con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teined therein. And if ſome makes eath, and others refuſes, he ſall arreiſt all the gudes perteining to the partie refuſand, and make compt thereof, as ſaid is. And what-ſome-ever gudes are not conteined in the Cocquet, to be confiſcat, as ſaid is.</p>
               <p>ITEM, It is ſtatute and ordeined, that all Marchants and Skippers, at the receaving of their cocquets in al parts and ports within this Realm, ſall giue their ſolemn eathes, and make faith in form and maner aboue expremed; and that they haue na for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bidden guds nor na other lawful guds or marchandize, except that whilk is conteined in their Cocquet and entres; and that they ſall take na other gudes in, all that voyage, vnder the pains foreſaids. Whilk eath ſall be made to the Cuſtomers, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>anent they ſall be anſwerable yearlie in the Exchecker.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="act">
               <head>
                  <hi>260</hi> Act of his Maieſties <hi>15</hi> Parliament the xix of December <hi>1597.</hi> Al Marchands should giue ane inventare of their mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandize and gudes to the Conſervatour.</head>
               <p>ITEM, every particular Marchant comming forth of the <hi>Law-cuntries</hi> to this Realme, ſall giue vp to the Conſervatour the ſpeciall quantitie of his gudes, and the qualitie thereof, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:11098:45"/> the in-barking of the ſamine gudes, vnder the paine of confiſcation thereof: And the Conſervatour to viſie and try the ſame at his pleaſure, to the effect that he may ſend hame ane Cockquet of the ſame, particularlie to his Majeſties Theſaurer, ſubſcryved be himſelf or his depute, for eſchewing of the fraud whilk may be vſed towards his Majeſtie in his cuſtomes.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="act">
            <head>Actes of Secreet Councell. <hi>APVD EDINBVRGH</hi> vigeſimo quinto die Menſis Octobris <hi>1611.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>OR-SA-MEIKLE As the Lords of ſecreit Councell vnderſtanding that his Majeſtie hes bene greatly hurt and prejudged in time bygain in the dew payment of his Heighnes cuſtomes, be reaſon of ſome Marchands, awners of gudes and geare tranſported out of this Realme, and in-broght within the ſamine for their awn advantage and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moditie, hes bene accuſtomed to pack and cloſe within packs and trees of grofwares and marchandize, paying ſmal cuſtome to his Heighnes; geare and marchandize of better value, and paying greater cuſtomes, and at the giving vp of the ſaid geare in entrie to his Heighnes Cuſtomers, hes given vp the ſame and payed cuſtome therefore, as for the grofwares conteined in the ſaid pack only. FOR remeed wherof, the ſaids Lords hes ſtatut and ordeined, that na Marchands take vpon hand at any tyme hereafter to pack or incloſe within packs of skins or other packs tranſported forth of this Realme, or within packs of lint or Hemp, trees of Carts, Cardes or Keames, or other packs or trees broght within this Cuntrie, any other geare or marchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dize
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:11098:46"/> of contrair nature, and conceale the ſamine vngiven vp in entrie to his Majeſties Cuſtomers, in defraud of his Heigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes dew cuſtomes, vnder the paine of eſcheating of the haill pack ſwa found, wherein the ſame geare ſall be ſwa found to be fraudfullie packed. AND TO THE EFFECT, that that nane pretend ignorance hereof, the ſaids Lords ordeins this preſent act to be imprinted, and letters to be direct for publication hereof at the market croſſes of the head burrowes of this Realme, and other places needfull.</p>
            <div type="act_and_ordinance">
               <head>Apud Edinburgh <hi>25</hi> die Menſis Octobris <hi>1611.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>THE Lords of ſecreit Councell, vnderſtanding the great hurt that his Majeſtie hes ſuſtained in tyme bygane, be cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taine Skippers, Maiſters and awners of ſhips, who in favours of the Marchant, and in defraud of his Majeſtie of the dew payment of his cuſtomes, laidens and loſſes their ſhips at vnfree Ports, and at Ports and harbories where his Heighnes he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na Cuſtomers. As lykwyſe, at their departing out of this Realme, after that they haue made and given vp to his Heighnes Cuſtomers the entrie of all gudes being within their ſhips and veſhels, and receaved their Cocquet there-vpon, they vſe to receaue within their ſaids ſhips other marchandize and gudes and tranſporteth the ſame out of this Cuntrie vncuſtomed, and at their returning hame againe, loſſes ane part of their laidning before they giue vp their entries to his Heighnes ſaids Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mers. FOR remeed whereof, the ſaids Lords hes ſtatute and ordeined, that na Maiſters, Marchants, Awners nor Skippers of Ships, Crears or others veſhels within this Realm, take vpon hand at any tyme here-after, to laiden or loſſe their ſhips in haill or in part at any vnfree Port within this Kingdome, or in any open Raids within the ſame, vnder the paine of eſcheating of the haill marchandize and gudes ſwa ſhipped or loſſed, and
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:11098:46"/> of the Ships, Crears and veſhels wherein the ſamine ſal be ſhip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped, and out of the whilk the ſamine ſall be loſſed. As lykwyſe, It is ſtatute and ordeined, that na Clerk of Cocquet giue or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyver any cocquet in time comming to any perſon, Marchand, skipper or others what-ſom-ever, vntil ſic time as the ſaid Clerk receaue an entrie ſubſcryved be the cuſtomer at the port where the gudes are ſhipped, whilk entrie ſall contein every particular marchands name with the quantitie and qualitie of the gudes pertaining to him, and the Cuſtomers certificat that he hes re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceaved the Kings Majeſties cuſtome of the ſame gudes, vnder the paine of deprivation of the ſaid Clerk of Cocquet from his office, and puniſhing him in his bodie, gudes and geare at the will and pleaſure of the ſaids Lords. As alſo, that na Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomer receaue an entrie of the gudes and marchandize be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in any ſhip to be tranſported out of this Kingdome, vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſe the preſenter thereof delyuer the ſamine ſubſcryved with his hand, and there-with-all ſolemnedlie make faith and ſweare in preſence of the ſaid Cuſtomer, Be GOD himſelfe his Creator, his part of Paradice, and as he ſall anſwere vpon the ſalvation and condemnation of his ſaull, that he hes na forbidden gudes nor geare, nor na other lawfull marchandize nor gudes within his ſaid Ship by and attour that whilk is conteined in the ſaid entrie ſubſcryved with his hand, nor that he knawes of nane to be brought within the ſaid Ship to be caryed away in her at that voyage, nor ſall not receaue there-after any gudes or geare to be laidned within his ſaid Shippe, and caryed away in her at that tyme. Whilk eath gif it be refuſed to be made, as ſaid is, It ſall be leſome to the ſaid Cuſtomer to arreiſt the ſaid Ship, and all the gudes and geare being therein. As lykwayes, It is ſtatute and ordai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, That na Maiſters, Awners nor Skippers of Shippes, paſſing out of this Realme take vpon hand at any tyme here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after, to receaue within their ſaids Ships and veſhels any mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandize
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:11098:47"/> gudes or geat to be tranſported out of the ſame after that they haue made and given vp their entres to his Heighnes Cuſtomers, vnder the paine of eſcheating of the marchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dize, gudes and geare ſa ſhipped, and of the Shippes, Crears, and veſhels wherein the famine ſall be ſhipped. As alſo, that na Maiſters, Awners nor Skippers of Shippes arryving within this Realme, take vpon hand at any tyme here-after, to loſſe any of the wynes, marchandize, gudes and geare, being within the ſame ſhips, vnder what-ſom-ever colour or pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence, at any Port or part within this Realme, or convoy any of the ſame away, in defraud of his Majeſties Cuſtomers, vntill ſic tyme as the entrie of their ſhips be made, and the ſame with the Cocquets receaved be them at the Port where they re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceaved their laidning be firſt delyvered to his Heighnes Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mers, and that they leaue no part of the ſaids wynes, marchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dize, gudes and geare vngiven vp in the ſaid entrie, nor con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceale no part thereof from the ſaids Cuſtomers, vnder the paine of eſcheating of the haill wynes, marchandize, gudes and geare ſwa to be loſſed out of the ſaids Ships, and of the ſhips, Crears and veſhels out of the whilk the famine ſall be loſſed. As alſo, vnder the paine of eſcheating of the haill marchandize, gudes and geare left out vngiven vp in the ſaid entrie. Whilk entrie ſall be given vp be the Skipper or Mai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter ſubſcryved with his hand, wha ſall be obleiſt ſolemnedlie to make faith, and ſweare be GOD himſelfe his Creator, his part of Paradice, and as he ſall anſwere to GOD vpon the ſal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation and condemnation of his ſaull, that the ſame is a juſt and trew entrie of the haill marchandize and gudes ſhipped within his ſhip at that voyage, and that he hes loſſed na part thereof, nor convoyed nane of the ſame away, before the giving vp of the ſaid entrie. Whilk eath, if it be refuſed to be made, as ſaid is, It ſall be leſome to the ſaids Cuſtomers to arreiſt the ſaid ſhip and haill gudes and marchandize being therein. And
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:11098:47"/> to the effect that nane of his Majeſties lieges pretend igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance hereof, the ſaids Lords ordains this act and ordinance to be imprinted, and publication hereof to be made at the market croſſes of the head burrowes of this Realme, and other places needfull.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="orders">
               <head>Apud Edinburgh <hi>25</hi> die Menſis Octobris <hi>1611.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>FOR-SA-MEIKLE, As for reformation of ſome abuſes practized by the Marchants carying gudes from <hi>Scotland</hi> to <hi>England,</hi> and from thence to <hi>Scotland,</hi> to the hurt and preju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dice of his Majeſties cuſtomes: It hath pleaſed his Heighnes to ſet downe theſe orders after-following to be obſerved in tyme comming, alſwell by the Marchands trafficking betwix the ſaids two Kingdomes, as by the Fermers and Tackſ-men of his Heighnes Cuſtomes of both the Realmes, <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>iz.</hi>
               </p>
               <div n="1" type="order">
                  <head>1</head>
                  <p>That the Farmers anc Tackſ-men of the cuſtomes of <hi>Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> doe keepe bookes of all the gudes that are entered and ſhipped for <hi>England,</hi> and alſo of all guds broght from <hi>England</hi> to <hi>Scotland,</hi> the ſhips name, place and Maiſters name, and to and from what Port the ſhip is bound, and to keepe the entreſſe of every Port ſeverallie.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="order">
                  <head>2</head>
                  <p>Alſo, that they keepe bookes of all gudes caried by land from <hi>Scotland</hi> to <hi>England,</hi> and from thence to <hi>Scotland,</hi> and to make certificat vnder the hand and ſeale of the Farmers and Tackſ-men or their deputes; expreſſing the Marchands name, the quantitie and qualitie of the gudes, to what place the ſame is caried, and the day of the Moneth and yeare, when and where the ſame was cuſtomed. The ſame forme and order to be obſerved by the Farmers of the cuſtome of <hi>England,</hi> and
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:11098:48"/> reciprocallie the Farmers and Tackſ-men of both the Realmes, to ſend every halfe yeare the coppies of theſe bookes, the ane to the other, <hi>Viz.</hi> at <hi>Chriſtmas</hi> and <hi>Midſommer.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="order">
                  <head>3</head>
                  <p>That all Cocquets or Certificats be made in the names of the principall awners of the gudes laiden in every Ship, and not in poore mens names, skairſlie knawne in <hi>Scotland</hi> or <hi>England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="order">
                  <head>4</head>
                  <p>That na Marchand or Tradiſ-man take vpon hand at any tyme hereafter, to cary by land any gudes from <hi>Scotland</hi> into <hi>England,</hi> or from <hi>England</hi> into <hi>Scotland</hi> by the waſte grounds or waſtes, bot that the ſame paſſe by the wayes of <hi>Aiton, Ied<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burgh, Kelſo, Drumfrice</hi> and <hi>Annand</hi> for <hi>Scotland;</hi> and by the wayes of <hi>Berwick</hi> and <hi>Carlile</hi> for <hi>England,</hi> vnder the paine of confiſcation of the gudes otherwayes caryed, or the value thereof to his Majeſties vſe after true tryell and examination taken therein.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="5" type="order">
                  <head>5</head>
                  <p>That the Farmers of the cuſtomes of both the Realmes, and their deputes, vpon the arryvall of any Ship from <hi>Scotland,</hi> and lykwyſe from <hi>England,</hi> ſall make dew examination of the gudes laiden with the Cocquets or Certificats for the ſame. And if they ſall finde a greater quantitie, or other guds then are ſpecified in the ſaids warrants, that they apprehend and ſtay the ſaids gudes, and take them into their poſſeſſion, vntill the Marchands awners thereof, or their factors in their names haue given ſufficient caution to his Majeſtie, for anſwering and pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the value of the ſaids gudes, into his Majeſties Exchecker of either Realmes, according as the ſame ſall be pryſed by twa honeſt men to be nominated, ane by the Marchand, the other by the Farmers and Tackſmen or their deputes, gif it ſall ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare vpon examination, that the ſaids gudes ſa ſtayed are vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed.
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:11098:48"/> The ſame order lykwiſe to be obſerved by ther Fer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mers and Tackſ-men, and their deputes for the land cariage.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="6" type="order">
                  <head>6</head>
                  <p>And that the Farmers and Tackſ-men of the Scots cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes doe every half yeare ſend to the Fermers of the Engliſh cuſtomes, all theſe bands for ſic ſurpluſage of gudes gif they be not diſcharged be certificate. The lyke to be done by the Fermers and Tackſ-men of the Engliſh cuſtomes.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="7" type="order">
                  <head>7</head>
                  <p>For the better obſerving of whilk orders and that nane pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend ignorance of the ſame, the Lords of his Heighnes privie Councell ordeins this preſent act and ordinance to be imprin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, and letters to be direct for publication of the ſame at the market croſſes of the head burrowes and Sea-ports of this Realme, and other places needfull. Commanding and char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging, all and ſundrie his Heighnes leiges and ſubjects whom the ſamine doth concerne, that they and everie ane of them inviolablie fulfill, obſerue and keepe everie Artickle aboue-written. As they will anſwere to the contrarie, vpon their heigheſt charge and perrell.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="act_and_ordinance">
               <head>Apud Edinburgh vigeſimo quinto die Menſis Octobris Anno Domini <hi>1611.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>FOR-SA-MEIKLE As it is vnderſtand to the Lords of ſecreit Councell, that be divers acts of Parliament, lawes and conſtitutions here-to-fore made and obſerved within this Realme, all maner of <hi>Engliſh</hi> gudes broght within the ſame hes bene ever in vſe of payment to his Majeſtie of a certaine cuſtom and duetie properlie apperteining to his Heighnes as a part of the patrimonie of his Crowne. As alſo, be act of ſecreet Councell, of the date the penult day of Februar 1589 yeares.
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:11098:49"/> Ratified and approven in the Parliament halden at <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> in the Moneth of June, ane thouſand, fiue hundreth, fourſcore twelue yeares, It is ſtatute and ordained, that all <hi>Engliſh</hi> cloth broght within this Realme, ſould be broght to his Heighnes Cuſtom-houſe: and there ſealed with ane ſeale appoynted then to be made to that effect. Whilk act tuke full execution vntill ſic tyme as his Majeſtie comming to his Crowne of <hi>England,</hi> did for a tyme forbid the taking of any cuſtome for marchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dize and gudes tranſported from the one Kingdome to the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, being the natiue commodities of the Land. And now ſince, It hath pleaſed his Majeſtie to take theſe cuſtomes in his awne hand againe, and to giue order and direction that the ſamine ſall be collected and vplifted in tyme comming to his Heighnes vſe. The Lords of ſecreet Councell hes found ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſare, meet and expedient, and decernes and ordains, that the foreſaid act ſall be revived againe, and ſtand in full force and effect in all tyme comming. And therefore ordaines the Tackſ-men of his Majeſties cuſtomes, to cauſe make and print ane ſeale and ſtamp of ſteele, conteining two halfes, for every Burgh and Sea Port within this Realme, whereas Cuſtomers are or ſall be eſtabliſhed, the ane halfe conteining <hi>IACOB<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S REX,</hi> with the Kings Majeſties Armes and Crowne; and the other half the name of the Burgh where the ſamine ſall remain. Whilk ſeall and ſtamp ſall be ſtricken and applyed to lead, and the ſamine lead being ſwa ſtrucken and printed with the ſame ſtampe ſall be hung to every peece or wob of claith, Cairſayes, Freeſe, Cottons, Baiſe or Fuſtians, that hereafter ſall be broght within this Realme forth of <hi>England</hi> be ſea or land, before the ſame be preſented to open market, ſauld or any waies diſponed vpon: And the ane halfe of the ſaid ſeale to be keeped be the Cuſtomer, and the other halfe be the Clerk of Cocquet. The awners of the ſaid claith, and others aboue-written, pay-and the cuſtome thereof, with ſic ane duetie for the ſeale as was
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:11098:49"/> accuſtomed to be payed of auld to the Cuſtomer and Clerk of Cocquet equallie betwix them. And to the end, that all <hi>Engliſh</hi> claith and others aboue-written, preſentlie remaining within this Realme, may be decerned and knawn from that whilk hereafter ſall be broght within the ſame, It is alſo de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned and ordained, that the Cuſtomer of every Burgh and Sea-port within this Realme, ſall repair to the dwelling-houſes and buithes of every ane of the ſaids Burrowes and Sea-ports whereof they are particularlie appointed Cuſtomers, and there receaue the eathes of the awners of ſic peeces and wobs of <hi>Engliſh</hi> claith, and others aboue ſpecified, as are therein, whither if the cuſtome thereof be payed or not, and where the cuſtome thereof is not payed, that they inſtantlie pay the ſame: And that the ſaid ſeall in taken thereof be hung thereto, and to all the other wobs and peeces of <hi>Engliſh</hi> claith, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers aboue-ſpecified, whilks ſall be apprehended within the ſaids buithes and houſes, whereof cuſtome hes bene payed of before for payment of the ſaid accuſtomed duetie for the ſaid ſeall allanerlie; and that the awners of the ſame claith and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers aboue ſpecified, requyre the Cuſtomers of every Burgh and Sea-port particularlie, to repare to their ſaids buithes and houſes to this effect, betwix and the <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> day of November next-to-come; and farther to doe and performe al other things whilk to every ane of them is appoynted to be done in maner foreſaid, vnder the paine of confiſcation of all the wobes and peeces of <hi>Engliſh</hi> claith, and others aboue-ſpecified, that ſall be apprehended thereafter wanting the ſaid ſeall. As alſo, to the effect his Heighnes Cuſtomes of all marchandize and gudes caryed from <hi>Scotland</hi> to <hi>England,</hi> and from thence to <hi>Scotland</hi> may be the mair trewlie payed, It is decerned, ſtatute and ordained, that na Marchands, their factours nor ſervants, Maiſters, Awners nor Skippers of Shippes, Barkes or others veſhels going from <hi>Scotland</hi> to <hi>England,</hi> take vpon hand at any
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:11098:50"/> tyme after the date hereof, to laiden any marchandize or guds within the ſame Ships, Barks or other veſhels, vntill ſic tyme as the ſame gudes and marchandize be firſt brought to his Heigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes Cuſtom-houſe, and the cuſtome thereof payed, and cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificat giuen be the Cuſtomer there-vpon. And that na Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chands, their factours nor ſervants cary any marchandize or gudes by land to <hi>England,</hi> vntill the ſame be firſt brought to his Heighnes Cuſtom-houſe, and the cuſtome thereof payed, and certificat given be the Cuſtomer there-vpon, vnder the paine of confiſcation of the haill marchandize and gudes ſwa ſhipped and laidned, with the Ships, Barks and other veſhels, wherein the ſame ſall happen to be ſhipped, and of the marchandize and gudes ſa caryed by land to his Heighnes vſe. And incaſe the ſame gudes and marchandize can not be apprehended, the awners thereof to make the juſt availl thereof forth-comming to his Heighnes vſe as eſcheat, dew tryell being taken there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>intill as effeirs. As lykwaies, that na Maiſters, Awners nor Skippers of Ships, Barkes or other veſhels, comming from <hi>England</hi> to <hi>Scotland,</hi> take vpon hand at any tyme after the date hereof, to loſſe any of the marchandize and gudes being there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in, till ſic tyme as they firſt enter their Ship in his Majeſties Cuſtom-houſe, giue vp ane trew inventar of the haill gudes and marchandize being therein to his Heighnes Cuſtomers, and there-with-all delyver vnto them the Cocquet receaved be them at the Port where the ſaid Ship was laidned, and make faith that the ſaid entrie ſa given vp be them, is trew, and that they haue not put on land at na Port, Harborie or other part what ſom-ever, any of the marchandize and gudes laidned within their ſaid Ship, but that the ſamine are all within her at the giving vp of the ſaid entrie, vnder the paine of confiſcation of the ſame Ships, Barks and other veſhels, or the juſt availl thereof to his Heighnes vſe. As alſo, the ſaids Lords, decernes and ordaines all and ſundrie his Heighnes ſubjects and ſtran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:11098:50"/> that at any tyme after the date hereof ſall happen to bring within this Realme, any marchandize or gudes be ſea or land from <hi>England,</hi> that they bring the ſame directlie to his Heigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes Cuſtom-houſe, and that they nor nane of them take vpon hand, to houſe, hyde, conceale, diſpone or make ſaill of any part thereof, vntill ſic tyme as his Heighnes cuſtomes thereof be firſt payed, and the Claith, Cairſays, Freeſe, Cottons, Baiſes and Fuſtians (incaſe any be) ſealed conforme to the order of auld and here eſtabliſhed, vnder the paine of confiſcation of the ſame marchandize and gudes ſa concealed and vncuſtomed, to his Heighnes vſe, where ever the ſame may be apprehended. And incaſe the ſamine can not be apprehended, the awners thereof to make the avail thereof forth-command to his Heigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes vſe as eſcheat, dew tryell being taken there-intill as effeirs. And becauſe the Marchands, awners of the ſaids marchandize and gudes caryed from <hi>Scotland</hi> to <hi>England,</hi> and from thence to <hi>Scotland,</hi> and the Maiſters, Awners and Skippers of the ſaids Ships and other veſhels, vſes ſic craft and policie in the quyet convoying away and concealing of the ſaids marchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dize and gudes, as ſom-tymes it is very hard and difficile to get the ſame apprehended, or ſufficient probation led there-into be witneſſes: The ſaids Lords of ſecreit Councell hes there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore found, decerned and declared, that the certificat of any of the Fermorers of his Heighnes cuſtomes in <hi>England,</hi> or of his Heighnes Cuſtomers or Comptrollers of his Heighnes cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes at any port or place be ſea or land within that Kingdom where cuſtomes are receaved and payed autentiklie, ſubſcry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved be any of their hands, bearing the day, moneth and yeare of the bringing of any of the ſaids marchandize and gudes from the ane Realme to the other; the Marchands name, Awner thereof, the quantitie and qualitie of the ſamine, the Shippes name, Maſter and Skipper thereof, wherein the ſamine is tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſported, ſall be als ſufficient probation againſt the Marchands,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:11098:51"/> and awners of the ſaids marchandize and gudes, and againſt the Maiſters, Awners and Skippers of the ſaids Ships, Barkes and other veſhels, as gif probation had bene led there in till be witneſſes. Whilk probation ſall be led before the Lords of his Heighnes privie Councell or Auditours of his Heighnes Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>checker. And for the better putting of this act and ordinance to execution, the ſaids Lords ordains and commands the Fer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morers of his Heighnes cuſtomes and their deputs, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers his Heighnes Cuſtomers and ſearchers, to paſſe, ſearch, ſeeke and apprehend all and ſundrie Engliſh cloth, Cairſayes, Freeſe, Cottons, Baiſe and Fuſtians whilk ſall be vnſealed, in maner aboue-written, in taken that the ſamine are cuſtomed, where ever the ſame can be apprehended, in open markets, faires, houſes, buithes, or other places what-ſom-ever within this Kingdome at any tyme after the ſaid <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> day of November next-to-come, and to confiſcat the ſame to his Heighnes vſe as vncuſtomed gudes. And to the effect that nane of his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties lieges or ſtrangers pretend ignorance hereof, the Lords of ſecreit Councell ordains this preſent act and ordinance to be imprinted, and letters to be direct for publication hereof at the market croſſes of the head Burrowes and Sea-ports of this Realme, and other places needfull in forme as offeirs.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:11098:51"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
